[{"answer": "D", "id": "E1A01", "question": "[97.301, 97.305]\r\nWhen using a transceiver that displays the carrier frequency of phone signals, which of the following displayed frequencies represents the highest frequency at which a properly adjusted USB emission will be totally within the band?\r\nA. The exact upper band edge\r\nB. 300 Hz below the upper band edge\r\nC. 1 kHz below the upper band edge\r\nD. 3 kHz below the upper band edge\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1A02", "question": "[97.301, 97.305]\r\nWhen using a transceiver that displays the carrier frequency of phone signals, which of the following displayed frequencies represents the lowest frequency at which a properly adjusted LSB emission will be totally within the band?\r\nA. The exact lower band edge\r\nB. 300 Hz above the lower band edge\r\nC. 1 kHz above the lower band edge\r\nD. 3 kHz above the lower band edge\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1A03", "question": "[97.301, 97.305]\r\nWith your transceiver displaying the carrier frequency of phone signals, you hear a DX station's CQ on 14.349 MHz USB. Is it legal to return the call using upper sideband on the same frequency?\r\nA. Yes, because the DX station initiated the contact\r\nB. Yes, because the displayed frequency is within the 20 meter band\r\nC. No, my sidebands will extend beyond the band edge \r\nD. No, USA stations are not permitted to use phone emissions above 14.340 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1A04", "question": "[97.301, 97.305]\r\nWith your transceiver displaying the carrier frequency of phone signals, you hear a DX station calling CQ on 3.601 MHz LSB. Is it legal to return the call using lower sideband on the same frequency?\r\nA. Yes, because the DX station initiated the contact\r\nB. Yes, because the displayed frequency is within the 75 meter phone band segment\r\nC. No, my sidebands will extend beyond the edge of the phone band segment\r\nD. No, USA stations are not permitted to use phone emissions below 3.610 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1A05", "question": "[97.313]\r\nWhat is the maximum power output permitted on the 60 meter band?\r\nA. 50 watts PEP effective radiated power relative to an isotropic radiator\r\nB. 50 watts PEP effective radiated power relative to a dipole\r\nC. 100 watts PEP effective radiated power relative to the gain of a half-wave dipole\r\nD. 100 watts PEP effective radiated power relative to an isotropic radiator\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1A06", "question": "[97.303]\r\nWhich of the following describes the rules for operation on the 60 meter band?\r\nA. Working DX is not permitted\r\nB. Operation is restricted to specific emission types and specific channels\r\nC. Operation is restricted to LSB\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1A07", "question": "[97.303]\r\nWhat is the only amateur band where transmission on specific channels rather than a range of frequencies is permitted? \r\nA. 12 meter band\r\nB. 17 meter band\r\nC. 30 meter band\r\nD. 60 meter band\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1A08", "question": "[97.219]\r\nIf a station in a message forwarding system inadvertently forwards a message that is in violation of FCC rules, who is primarily accountable for the rules violation?\r\nA. The control operator of the packet bulletin board station\r\nB. The control operator of the originating station\r\nC. The control operators of all the stations in the system\r\nD. The control operators of all the stations in the system not authenticating the source from which they accept communications\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1A09", "question": "[97.219]\r\nWhat is the first action you should take if your digital message forwarding station inadvertently forwards a communication that violates FCC rules?\r\nA. Discontinue forwarding the communication as soon as you become aware of it\r\nB. Notify the originating station that the communication does not comply with FCC rules\r\nC. Notify the nearest FCC Field Engineer's office\r\nD. Discontinue forwarding all messages\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1A10", "question": "[97.11]\r\nIf an amateur station is installed aboard a ship or aircraft, what condition must be met before the station is operated?\r\nA. Its operation must be approved by the master of the ship or the pilot in command of the aircraft\r\nB. The amateur station operator must agree to not transmit when the main ship or aircraft radios are in use\r\nC. It must have a power supply that is completely independent of the main ship or aircraft power supply\r\nD. Its operator must have an FCC Marine or Aircraft endorsement on his or her amateur license\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1A11", "question": "[97.5]\r\nWhat authorization or licensing is required when operating an amateur station aboard a US-registered vessel in international waters?\r\nA. Any amateur license with an FCC Marine or Aircraft endorsement\r\nB. Any FCC-issued amateur license or a reciprocal permit for an alien amateur licensee\r\nC. Only General class or higher amateur licenses\r\nD. An unrestricted Radiotelephone Operator Permit\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1A12", "question": "[97.301, 97.305]\r\nWith your transceiver displaying the carrier frequency of CW signals, you hear a DX station's CQ on 3.500 MHz. Is it legal to return the call using CW on the same frequency?\r\nA. Yes, the DX station initiated the contact\r\nB. Yes, the displayed frequency is within the 80 meter CW band segment\r\nC. No, sidebands from the CW signal will be out of the band.\r\nD. No, USA stations are not permitted to use CW emissions below 3.525 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1A13", "question": "[97.5]\r\nWho must be in physical control of the station apparatus of an amateur station aboard any vessel or craft that is documented or registered in the United States?\r\nA. Only a person with an FCC Marine Radio \r\nB. Any person holding an FCC-issued amateur license or who is authorized for alien reciprocal operation\r\nC. Only a person named in an amateur station license grant\r\nD. Any person named in an amateur station license grant or a person holding an unrestricted Radiotelephone Operator Permit  \r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1B01", "question": "[97.3]\r\nWhich of the following constitutes a spurious emission?\r\nA. An amateur station transmission made at random without the proper call sign identification\r\nB. A signal transmitted to prevent its detection by any station other than the intended recipient\r\nC. Any transmitted bogus signal that interferes with another licensed radio station\r\nD. An emission outside its necessary bandwidth that can be reduced or eliminated without affecting the information transmitted\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1B02", "question": "[97.13]\r\nWhich of the following factors might cause the physical location of an amateur station apparatus or antenna structure to be restricted?\r\nA. The location is near an area of political conflict \r\nB. The location is of geographical or horticultural importance \r\nC. The location is in an ITU zone designated for coordination with one or more foreign governments\r\nD. The location is of environmental importance or significant in American history, architecture, or culture\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1B03", "question": "[97.13]\r\nWithin what distance must an amateur station protect an FCC monitoring facility from harmful interference?\r\nA. 1 mile\r\nB. 3 miles\r\nC. 10 miles\r\nD. 30 miles\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1B04", "question": "[97.13, 1.1305-1.1319]\r\nWhat must be done before placing an amateur station within an officially designated wilderness area or wildlife preserve, or an area listed in the National Register of Historical Places?\r\nA. A proposal must be submitted to the National Park Service\r\nB. A letter of intent must be filed with the National Audubon Society\r\nC. An Environmental Assessment must be submitted to the FCC\r\nD. A form FSD-15 must be submitted to the Department of the Interior\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1B05", "question": "[97.303]\r\nWhat is the maximum bandwidth for a data emission on 60 meters?\r\nA. 60 Hz\r\nB. 170 Hz\r\nC. 1.5 kHz\r\nD. 2.8 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1B06", "question": "[97.15]\r\nWhich of the following additional rules apply if you are installing an amateur station antenna at a site at or near a public use airport?\r\nA. You may have to notify the Federal Aviation Administration and register it with the FCC as required by Part 17 of FCC rules\r\nB. No special rules apply if your antenna structure will be less than 300 feet in height\r\nC. You must file an Environmental Impact Statement with the EPA before construction begins\r\nD. You must obtain a construction permit from the airport zoning authority\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1B07", "question": "[97.15]\r\nWhere must the carrier frequency of a CW signal be set to comply with FCC rules for 60 meter operation?\r\nA. At the lowest frequency of the channel\r\nB. At the center frequency of the channel\r\nC. At the highest frequency of the channel\r\nD. On any frequency where the signal's sidebands are within the channel\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1B08", "question": "[97.121]\r\nWhat limitations may the FCC place on an amateur station if its signal causes interference to domestic broadcast reception, assuming that the receiver(s) involved are of good engineering design?\r\nA. The amateur station must cease operation\r\nB. The amateur station must cease operation on all frequencies below 30 MHz\r\nC. The amateur station must cease operation on all frequencies above 30 MHz\r\nD. The amateur station must avoid transmitting during certain hours on frequencies that cause the interference\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1B09", "question": "[97.407]\r\nWhich amateur stations may be operated in RACES?\r\nA. Only those club stations licensed to Amateur Extra class operators\r\nB. Any FCC-licensed amateur station except a Technician class operator's station\r\nC. Any FCC-licensed amateur station certified by the responsible civil defense organization for the area served\r\nD. Any FCC-licensed amateur station participating in the Military Affiliate Radio System (MARS)\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1B10", "question": "[97.407]\r\nWhat frequencies are authorized to an amateur station participating in RACES?\r\nA. All amateur service frequencies authorized to the control operator\r\nB. Specific segments in the amateur service MF, HF, VHF and UHF bands\r\nC. Specific local government channels\r\nD. Military Affiliate Radio System (MARS) channels\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1B11", "question": "[97.307]\r\nWhat is the permitted mean power of any spurious emission relative to the mean power of the fundamental emission from a station transmitter or external RF amplifier installed after January 1, 2003, and transmitting on a frequency below 30 MHZ?\r\nA. At least 43 dB below\r\nB. At least 53 dB below\r\nC. At least 63 dB below\r\nD. At least 73 dB below\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1B12", "question": "[97.307]\r\nWhat is the highest modulation index permitted at the highest modulation frequency for angle modulation?\r\nA. .5\r\nB. 1.0\r\nC. 2.0\r\nD. 3.0\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1C01", "question": "[97.3]\r\nWhat is a remotely controlled station?\r\nA. A station operated away from its regular home location\r\nB. A station controlled by someone other than the licensee\r\nC. A station operating under automatic control\r\nD. A station controlled indirectly through a control link\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1C02", "question": "[97.3, 97.109]\r\nWhat is meant by automatic control of a station?\r\nA. The use of devices and procedures for control so that the control operator does not have to be present at a control point\r\nB. A station operating with its output power controlled automatically\r\nC. Remotely controlling a station's antenna pattern through a directional control link\r\nD. The use of a control link between a control point and a locally controlled station\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1C03", "question": "[97.3, 97.109]\r\nHow do the control operator responsibilities of a station under automatic control differ from one under local control?\r\nA. Under local control there is no control operator\r\nB. Under automatic control the control operator is not required to be present at the control point\r\nC. Under automatic control there is no control operator\r\nD. Under local control a control operator is not required to be present at a control point\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1C04", "question": "[97.109]\r\nWhen may an automatically controlled station retransmit third party communications?\r\nA. Never\r\nB. Only when transmitting RTTY or data emissions\r\nC. When specifically agreed upon by the sending and receiving stations\r\nD. When approved by the National Telecommunication and Information Administration\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E1C05", "question": "[97.109]\r\nWhen may an automatically controlled station originate third party communications?\r\nA. Never\r\nB. Only when transmitting an RTTY or data emissions\r\nC. When specifically agreed upon by the sending and receiving stations\r\nD. When approved by the National Telecommunication and Information Administration\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1C06", "question": "[97.109]\r\nWhich of the following statements concerning remotely controlled amateur stations is true?\r\nA. Only Extra Class operators may be the control operator of a remote station\r\nB. A control operator need not be present at the control point\r\nC. A control operator must be present at the control point\r\nD. Repeater and auxiliary stations may not be remotely controlled\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E1C07", "question": "[97.3]\r\nWhat is meant by local control?\r\nA. Controlling a station through a local auxiliary link\r\nB. Automatically manipulating local station controls \r\nC. Direct manipulation of the transmitter by a control operator\r\nD. Controlling a repeater using a portable handheld transceiver\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1C08", "question": "[97.213]\r\nWhat is the maximum permissible duration of a remotely controlled station's transmissions if its control link malfunctions?\r\nA. 30 seconds\r\nB. 3 minutes \r\nC. 5 minutes\r\nD. 10 minutes\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E1C09", "question": "[97.205]\r\nWhich of these frequencies are available for an automatically controlled repeater operating below 30 MHz?\r\nA. 18.110 - 18.168 MHz\r\nB. 24.940 - 24.990 MHz \r\nC. 10.100 - 10.150 MHz\r\nD. 29.500 - 29.700 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E1C10", "question": "[97.113]\r\nWhat types of amateur stations may automatically retransmit the radio signals of other amateur stations?\r\nA. Only beacon, repeater or space stations\r\nB. Only auxiliary, repeater or space stations\r\nC. Only earth stations, repeater stations or model craft\r\nD. Only auxiliary, beacon or space stations\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2A01", "question": "What is the direction of an ascending pass for an amateur satellite?\r\nA. From west to east\r\nB. From east to west\r\nC. From south to north\r\nD. From north to south\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2A02", "question": "What is the direction of a descending pass for an amateur satellite?\r\nA. From north to south\r\nB. From west to east\r\nC. From east to west\r\nD. From south to north\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2A03", "question": "What is the orbital period of an Earth satellite?\r\nA. The point of maximum height of a satellite's orbit\r\nB. The point of minimum height of a satellite's orbit\r\nC. The time it takes for a satellite to complete one revolution around the Earth\r\nD. The time it takes for a satellite to travel from perigee to apogee\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2A04", "question": "What is meant by the term mode as applied to an amateur radio satellite?\r\nA. The type of signals that can be relayed through the satellite\r\nB. The satellite's uplink and downlink frequency bands\r\nC. The satellite's orientation with respect to the Earth\r\nD. Whether the satellite is in a polar or equatorial orbit\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2A05", "question": "What do the letters in a satellite's mode designator specify?\r\nA. Power limits for uplink and downlink transmissions\r\nB. The location of the ground control station\r\nC. The polarization of uplink and downlink signals\r\nD. The uplink and downlink frequency ranges\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2A06", "question": "On what band would a satellite receive signals if it were operating in mode U/V?\r\nA. 435-438 MHz\r\nB. 144-146 MHz\r\nC. 50.0-50.2 MHz\r\nD. 29.5 to 29.7 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2A07", "question": "Which of the following types of signals can be relayed through a linear transponder?\r\nA. FM and CW\r\nB. SSB and SSTV\r\nC. PSK and Packet\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2A08", "question": "Why should effective radiated power to a satellite which uses a linear transponder be limited?\r\nA. To prevent creating errors in the satellite telemetry\r\nB. To avoid reducing the downlink power to all other users\r\nC. To prevent the satellite from emitting out of band signals\r\nD. To avoid interfering with terrestrial QSOs\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2A09", "question": "What do the terms L band and S band specify with regard to satellite communications?\r\nA. The 23 centimeter and 13 centimeter bands\r\nB. The 2 meter and 70 centimeter bands\r\nC. FM and Digital Store-and-Forward systems\r\nD. Which sideband to use\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2A10", "question": "Why may the received signal from an amateur satellite exhibit a rapidly repeating fading effect?\r\nA. Because the satellite is spinning\r\nB. Because of ionospheric absorption\r\nC. Because of the satellite's low orbital altitude\r\nD. Because of the Doppler Effect\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2A11", "question": "What type of antenna can be used to minimize the effects of spin modulation and Faraday rotation?\r\nA. A linearly polarized antenna\r\nB. A circularly polarized antenna\r\nC. An isotropic antenna\r\nD. A log-periodic dipole array\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2A12", "question": "What is one way to predict the location of a satellite at a given time?\r\nA. By means of the Doppler data for the specified satellite\r\nB. By subtracting the mean anomaly from the orbital inclination\r\nC. By adding the mean anomaly to the orbital inclination\r\nD. By calculations using the Keplerian elements for the specified satellite\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2A13", "question": "What type of satellite appears to stay in one position in the sky?\r\nA. HEO\r\nB. Geostationary\r\nC. Geomagnetic\r\nD. LEO\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2B01", "question": "How many times per second is a new frame transmitted in a fast-scan (NTSC) television system?\r\nA. 30\r\nB. 60\r\nC. 90\r\nD. 120\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2B02", "question": "How many horizontal lines make up a fast-scan (NTSC) television frame?\r\nA. 30\r\nB. 60\r\nC. 525\r\nD. 1080\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B03", "question": "How is an interlaced scanning pattern generated in a fast-scan (NTSC) television system?\r\nA. By scanning two fields simultaneously\r\nB. By scanning each field from bottom to top\r\nC. By scanning lines from left to right in one field and right to left in the next\r\nD. By scanning odd numbered lines in one field and even numbered ones in the next\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2B04", "question": "What is blanking in a video signal?\r\nA. Synchronization of the horizontal and vertical sync pulses\r\nB. Turning off the scanning beam while it is traveling from right to left or from bottom to top\r\nC. Turning off the scanning beam at the conclusion of a transmission\r\nD. Transmitting a black and white test pattern\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2B05", "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using vestigial sideband for standard fast- scan TV transmissions? \r\nA. The vestigial sideband carries the audio information\r\nB. The vestigial sideband contains chroma information\r\nC. Vestigial sideband reduces bandwidth while allowing for simple video detector circuitry \r\nD. Vestigial sideband provides high frequency emphasis to sharpen the picture\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2B06", "question": "What is vestigial sideband modulation?\r\nA. Amplitude modulation in which one complete sideband and a portion of the other are transmitted\r\nB. A type of modulation in which one sideband is inverted \r\nC. Narrow-band FM transmission achieved by filtering one sideband from the audio before frequency modulating the carrier \r\nD. Spread spectrum modulation achieved by applying FM modulation following single sideband amplitude modulation\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2B07", "question": "What is the name of the signal component that carries color information in NTSC video?\r\nA. Luminance\r\nB. Chroma\r\nC. Hue\r\nD. Spectral Intensity\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B08", "question": "Which of the following is a common method of transmitting accompanying audio with amateur fast-scan television?\r\nA. Frequency-modulated sub-carrier\r\nB. A separate VHF or UHF audio link\r\nC. Frequency modulation of the video carrier\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B09", "question": "What hardware, other than a receiver with SSB capability and a suitable computer, is needed to decode SSTV using Digital Radio Mondiale (DRM)?\r\nA. A special IF converter \r\nB. A special front end limiter\r\nC. A special notch filter to remove synchronization pulses\r\nD. No other hardware is needed\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2B10", "question": "Which of the following is an acceptable bandwidth for Digital Radio Mondiale (DRM) based voice or SSTV digital transmissions made on the HF amateur bands?\r\nA. 3 KHz\r\nB. 10 KHz\r\nC. 15 KHz\r\nD. 20 KHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2B11", "question": "What is the function of the Vertical Interval Signaling (VIS) code transmitted as part of an SSTV transmission?\r\nA. To lock the color burst oscillator in color SSTV images\r\nB. To identify the SSTV mode being used\r\nC. To provide vertical synchronization\r\nD. To identify the call sign of the station transmitting\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B12", "question": "How are analog SSTV images typically transmitted on the HF bands?\r\nA. Video is converted to equivalent Baudot representation\r\nB. Video is converted to equivalent ASCII representation\r\nC. Varying tone frequencies representing the video are transmitted using PSK\r\nD. Varying tone frequencies representing the video are transmitted using single sideband\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2B13", "question": "How many lines are commonly used in each frame on an amateur slow-scan color television picture?\r\nA. 30 to 60\r\nB. 60 or 100\r\nC. 128 or 256\r\nD. 180 or 360\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2B14", "question": "What aspect of an amateur slow-scan television signal encodes the brightness of the picture?\r\nA. Tone frequency\r\nB. Tone amplitude\r\nC. Sync amplitude\r\nD. Sync frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2B15", "question": "What signals SSTV receiving equipment to begin a new picture line?\r\nA. Specific tone frequencies\r\nB. Elapsed time\r\nC. Specific tone amplitudes\r\nD. A two-tone signal\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B16", "question": "Which of the following is the video standard used by North American Fast Scan ATV stations?\r\nA. PAL\r\nB. DRM\r\nC. Scottie\r\nD. NTSC\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2B17", "question": "What is the approximate bandwidth of a slow-scan TV signal?\r\nA. 600 Hz\r\nB. 3 kHz\r\nC. 2 MHz\r\nD. 6 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2B18", "question": "On which of the following frequencies is one likely to find FM ATV transmissions?\r\nA. 14.230 MHz\r\nB. 29.6 MHz\r\nC. 52.525 MHz\r\nD. 1255 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2B19", "question": "What special operating frequency restrictions are imposed on slow scan TV transmissions?\r\nA. None; they are allowed on all amateur frequencies\r\nB. They are restricted to 7.245 MHz, 14.245 MHz, 21.345, MHz, and 28.945 MHz\r\nC. They are restricted to phone band segments and their bandwidth can be no greater than that of a voice signal of the same modulation type\r\nD. They are not permitted above 54 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C01", "question": "Which of the following is true about contest operating?\r\nA. Operators are permitted to make contacts even if they do not submit a log\r\nB. Interference to other amateurs is unavoidable and therefore acceptable\r\nC. It is mandatory to transmit the call sign of the station being worked as part of every transmission to that station\r\nD. Every contest requires a signal report in the exchange\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C02", "question": "Which of the following best describes the term \"self-spotting\" in regards to contest operating?\r\nA. The generally prohibited practice of posting one's own call sign and frequency on a call sign spotting network\r\nB. The acceptable practice of manually posting the call signs of stations on a call sign spotting network\r\nC. A manual technique for rapidly zero beating or tuning to a station's frequency before calling that station\r\nD. An automatic method for rapidly zero beating or tuning to a station's frequency before calling that station\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C03", "question": "From which of the following bands is amateur radio contesting generally excluded?\r\nA. 30 meters\r\nB. 6 meters\r\nC. 2 meters\r\nD. 33 cm\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2C04", "question": "On which of the following frequencies is an amateur radio contest contact generally discouraged?\r\nA. 3.525 MHz\r\nB. 14.020 MHz\r\nC. 28.330 MHz\r\nD. 146.52 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2C05", "question": "What is the function of a DX QSL Manager?\r\nA. To allocate frequencies for DXpeditions\r\nB. To handle the receiving and sending of confirmation cards for a DX station\r\nC. To run a net to allow many stations to contact a rare DX station\r\nD. To relay calls to and from a DX station\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E2C06", "question": "During a VHF/UHF contest, in which band segment would you expect to find the highest level of activity?\r\nA. At the top of each band, usually in a segment reserved for contests\r\nB. In the middle of each band, usually on the national calling frequency\r\nC. In the weak signal segment of the band, with most of the activity near the calling frequency\r\nD. In the middle of the band, usually 25 kHz above the national calling frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C07", "question": "What is the Cabrillo format?\r\nA. A standard for submission of electronic contest logs\r\nB. A method of exchanging information during a contest QSO\r\nC. The most common set of contest rules\r\nD. The rules of order for meetings between contest sponsors\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C08", "question": "Why are received spread-spectrum signals resistant to interference?\r\nA. Signals not using the spectrum-spreading algorithm are suppressed in the receiver\r\nB. The high power used by a spread-spectrum transmitter keeps its signal from being easily overpowered\r\nC. The receiver is always equipped with a digital blanker circuit \r\nD. If interference is detected by the receiver it will signal the transmitter to change frequencies\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2C09", "question": "How does the spread-spectrum technique of frequency hopping work?\r\nA. If interference is detected by the receiver it will signal the transmitter to change frequencies\r\nB. If interference is detected by the receiver it will signal the transmitter to wait until the frequency is clear\r\nC. A pseudo-random binary bit stream is used to shift the phase of an RF carrier very rapidly in a particular sequence\r\nD. The frequency of the transmitted signal is changed very rapidly according to a particular sequence also used by the receiving station\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E2C10", "question": "Why might a DX station state that they are listening on another frequency?\r\nA. Because the DX station may be transmitting on a frequency that is prohibited to some responding stations\r\nB. To separate the calling stations from the DX station\r\nC. To reduce interference, thereby improving operating efficiency \r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E2C11", "question": "How should you generally identify your station when attempting to contact a DX station working a pileup or in a contest?\r\nA. Send your full call sign once or twice\r\nB. Send only the last two letters of your call sign until you make contact\r\nC. Send your full call sign and grid square\r\nD. Send the call sign of the DX station three times, the words this is, then your call sign three times\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E2C12", "question": "What might help to restore contact when DX signals become too weak to copy across an entire HF band a few hours after sunset?\r\nA. Switch to a higher frequency HF band\r\nB. Switch to a lower frequency HF band\r\nC. Wait 90 minutes or so for the signal degradation to pass\r\nD. Wait 24 hours before attempting another communication on the band\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3A01", "question": "What is the approximate maximum separation measured along the surface of the Earth between two stations communicating by Moon bounce?\r\nA. 500 miles, if the Moon is at perigee\r\nB. 2000 miles, if the Moon is at apogee\r\nC. 5000 miles, if the Moon is at perigee\r\nD. 12,000 miles, as long as both can \"see\" the Moon\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3A02", "question": "What characterizes libration fading of an Earth-Moon-Earth signal?\r\nA. A slow change in the pitch of the CW signal\r\nB. A fluttery irregular fading\r\nC. A gradual loss of signal as the Sun rises\r\nD. The returning echo is several Hertz lower in frequency than the transmitted signal\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3A03", "question": "When scheduling EME contacts, which of these conditions will generally result in the least path loss?\r\nA. When the Moon is at perigee\r\nB. When the Moon is full\r\nC. When the Moon is at apogee\r\nD. When the MUF is above 30 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3A04", "question": "What type of receiving system is desirable for EME communications?\r\nA. Equipment with very wide bandwidth\r\nB. Equipment with very low dynamic range\r\nC. Equipment with very low gain\r\nD. Equipment with very low noise figures\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3A05", "question": "Which of the following describes a method of establishing EME contacts?\r\nA. Time synchronous transmissions with each station alternating\r\nB. Storing and forwarding digital messages\r\nC. Judging optimum transmission times by monitoring beacons from the Moon\r\nD. High speed CW identification to avoid fading\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3A06", "question": "What frequency range would you normally tune to find EME signals in the 2 meter band?\r\nA. 144.000 - 144.001 MHz\r\nB. 144.000 - 144.100 MHz\r\nC. 144.100 - 144.300 MHz\r\nD. 145.000 - 145.100 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3A07", "question": "What frequency range would you normally tune to find EME signals in the 70 cm band?\r\nA. 430.000 - 430.150 MHz\r\nB. 430.100 - 431.100 MHz\r\nC. 431.100 - 431.200 MHz\r\nD. 432.000 - 432.100 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3A08", "question": "When a meteor strikes the Earth's atmosphere, a cylindrical region of free electrons is formed at what layer of the ionosphere?\r\nA. The E layer\r\nB. The F1 layer\r\nC. The F2 layer\r\nD. The D layer\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3A09", "question": "Which of the following frequency ranges is well suited for meteor-scatter communications?\r\nA. 1.8 - 1.9 MHz\r\nB. 10 - 14 MHz\r\nC. 28 - 148 MHz\r\nD. 220 - 450 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3A10", "question": "Which of the following is a good technique for making meteor-scatter contacts?\r\nA. 15 second timed transmission sequences with stations alternating based on location\r\nB. Use of high speed CW or digital modes\r\nC. Short transmission with rapidly repeated call signs and signal reports\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3B01", "question": "What is transequatorial propagation?\r\nA. Propagation between two mid-latitude points at approximately the same distance north and south of the magnetic equator\r\nB. Propagation between any two points located on the magnetic equator\r\nC. Propagation between two continents by way of ducts along the magnetic equator\r\nD. Propagation between two stations at the same latitude\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3B02", "question": "What is the approximate maximum range for signals using transequatorial propagation?\r\nA. 1000 miles\r\nB. 2500 miles\r\nC. 5000 miles\r\nD. 7500 miles\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3B03", "question": "What is the best time of day for transequatorial propagation?\r\nA. Morning\r\nB. Noon\r\nC. Afternoon or early evening\r\nD. Late at night\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3B04", "question": "What type of propagation is probably occurring if an HF beam antenna must be pointed in a direction 180 degrees away from a station to receive the strongest signals?\r\nA. Long-path\r\nB. Sporadic-E\r\nC. Transequatorial\r\nD. Auroral\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3B05", "question": "Which amateur bands typically support long-path propagation?\r\nA. 160 to 40 meters\r\nB. 30 to 10 meters\r\nC. 160 to 10 meters\r\nD. 6 meters to 2 meters\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3B06", "question": "Which of the following amateur bands most frequently provides long-path propagation?\r\nA. 80 meters\r\nB. 20 meters\r\nC. 10 meters\r\nD. 6 meters\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3B07", "question": "Which of the following could account for hearing an echo on the received signal of a distant station?\r\nA. High D layer absorption\r\nB. Meteor scatter\r\nC. Transmit frequency is higher than the MUF\r\nD. Receipt of a signal by more than one path\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3B08", "question": "What type of HF propagation is probably occurring if radio signals travel along the terminator between daylight and darkness?\r\nA. Transequatorial\r\nB. Sporadic-E\r\nC. Long-path\r\nD. Gray-line\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3B09", "question": "At what time of day is gray-line propagation most likely to occur?\r\nA. At sunrise and sunset\r\nB. When the Sun is directly above the location of the transmitting station\r\nC. When the Sun is directly overhead at the middle of the communications path between the two stations\r\nD. When the Sun is directly above the location of the receiving station\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3B10", "question": "What is the cause of gray-line propagation?\r\nA. At midday, the Sun being directly overhead superheats the ionosphere causing increased refraction of radio waves\r\nB. At twilight, D-layer absorption drops while E-layer and F-layer propagation remain strong \r\nC. In darkness, solar absorption drops greatly while atmospheric ionization remains steady\r\nD. At mid afternoon, the Sun heats the ionosphere decreasing radio wave refraction and the MUF\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3B11", "question": "Which of the following describes gray-line propagation?\r\nA. Backscatter contacts on the 10 meter band\r\nB. Over the horizon propagation on the 6 and 2 meter bands\r\nC. Long distance communications at twilight on frequencies less than 15 MHz\r\nD. Tropospheric propagation on the 2 meter and 70 centimeter bands\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3C01", "question": "Which of the following effects does Aurora activity have on radio communications?\r\nA. SSB signals are raspy\r\nB. Signals propagating through the Aurora are fluttery\r\nC. CW signals appear to be modulated by white noise\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3C02", "question": "What is the cause of Aurora activity?\r\nA. The interaction between the solar wind and the Van Allen belt\r\nB. A low sunspot level combined with tropospheric ducting\r\nC. The interaction of charged particles from the Sun with the Earth's magnetic field and the ionosphere\r\nD. Meteor showers concentrated in the northern latitudes\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3C03", "question": "Where in the ionosphere does Aurora activity occur?\r\nA. In the F1-region \r\nB. In the F2-region\r\nC. In the D-region \r\nD. In the E-region\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3C04", "question": "Which emission mode is best for Aurora propagation?\r\nA. CW\r\nB. SSB\r\nC. FM\r\nD. RTTY\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3C05", "question": "Which of the following describes selective fading?\r\nA. Variability of signal strength with beam heading\r\nB. Partial cancellation of some frequencies within the received pass band\r\nC. Sideband inversion within the ionosphere\r\nD. Degradation of signal strength due to backscatter\r\n\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3C06", "question": "By how much does the VHF/UHF radio-path horizon distance exceed the geometric horizon?\r\nA. By approximately 15% of the distance\r\nB. By approximately twice the distance\r\nC. By approximately one-half the distance\r\nD. By approximately four times the distance\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3C07", "question": "How does the radiation pattern of a horizontally polarized 3-element beam antenna vary with its height above ground?\r\nA. The main lobe takeoff angle increases with increasing height\r\nB. The main lobe takeoff angle decreases with increasing height\r\nC. The horizontal beam width increases with height\r\nD. The horizontal beam width decreases with height\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3C08", "question": "What is the name of the high-angle wave in HF propagation that travels for some distance within the F2 region?\r\nA. Oblique-angle ray\r\nB. Pedersen ray\r\nC. Ordinary ray\r\nD. Heaviside ray\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3C09", "question": "Which of the following is usually responsible for causing VHF signals to propagate for hundreds of miles?\r\nA. D-region absorption\r\nB. Faraday rotation\r\nC. Tropospheric ducting\r\nD. Ground wave\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3C10", "question": "How does the performance of a horizontally polarized antenna mounted on the side of a hill compare with the same antenna mounted on flat ground?\r\nA. The main lobe takeoff angle increases in the downhill direction\r\nB. The main lobe takeoff angle decreases in the downhill direction\r\nC. The horizontal beam width decreases in the downhill direction\r\nD. The horizontal beam width increases in the uphill direction\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E3C11", "question": "From the contiguous 48 states, in which approximate direction should an antenna be pointed to take maximum advantage of aurora propagation?\r\nA. South\r\nB. North\r\nC. East\r\nD. West\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E3C12", "question": "How does the maximum distance of ground-wave propagation change when the signal frequency is increased?\r\nA. It stays the same\r\nB. It increases\r\nC. It decreases\r\nD. It peaks at roughly 14 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E3C13", "question": "What type of polarization is best for ground-wave propagation?\r\nA. Vertical\r\nB. Horizontal\r\nC. Circular\r\nD. Elliptical\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E3C14", "question": "Why does the radio-path horizon distance exceed the geometric horizon?\r\nA. E-region skip\r\nB. D-region skip\r\nC. Downward bending due to aurora refraction\r\nD. Downward bending due to density variations in the atmosphere\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4A01", "question": "How does a spectrum analyzer differ from an oscilloscope?\r\nA. A spectrum analyzer measures ionospheric reflection; an oscilloscope displays electrical signals\r\nB. A spectrum analyzer displays the peak amplitude of signals; an oscilloscope displays the average amplitude of signals\r\nC. A spectrum analyzer displays signals in the frequency domain; an oscilloscope displays signals in the time domain\r\nD. A spectrum analyzer displays radio frequencies; an oscilloscope displays audio frequencies\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4A02", "question": "Which of the following parameters would a spectrum analyzer display on the horizontal axis?\r\nA. SWR\r\nB. Q\r\nC. Time\r\nD. Frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4A03", "question": "Which of the following parameters would a spectrum analyzer display on the vertical axis? \r\nA. Amplitude\r\nB. Duration\r\nC. SWR\r\nD. Q\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4A04", "question": "Which of the following test instruments is used to display spurious signals from a radio transmitter?\r\nA. A spectrum analyzer\r\nB. A wattmeter\r\nC. A logic analyzer\r\nD. A time-domain reflectometer\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4A05", "question": "Which of the following test instruments is used to display intermodulation distortion products in an SSB transmission?\r\nA. A wattmeter\r\nB. A spectrum analyzer\r\nC. A logic analyzer\r\nD. A time-domain reflectometer\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4A06", "question": "Which of the following could be determined with a spectrum analyzer?\r\nA. The degree of isolation between the input and output ports of a 2 meter duplexer\r\nB. Whether a crystal is operating on its fundamental or overtone frequency\r\nC. The spectral output of a transmitter\r\nD. All of these choices are correct \r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4A07", "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using an antenna analyzer compared to an SWR bridge to measure antenna SWR?\r\nA. Antenna analyzers automatically tune your antenna for resonance\r\nB. Antenna analyzers do not need an external RF source \r\nC. Antenna analyzers display a time-varying representation of the modulation envelope\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4A08", "question": "Which of the following instruments would be best for measuring the SWR of a beam antenna?\r\nA. A spectrum analyzer\r\nB. A Q meter\r\nC. An ohmmeter\r\nD. An antenna analyzer\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4A09", "question": "Which of the following describes a good method for measuring the intermodulation distortion of your own PSK signal?\r\nA. Transmit into a dummy load, receive the signal on a second receiver, and feed the audio into the sound card of a computer running an appropriate PSK program\r\nB. Multiply the ALC level on the transmitter during a normal transmission by the average power output\r\nC. Use an RF voltmeter coupled to the transmitter output using appropriate isolation to prevent damage to the meter\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4A10", "question": "Which of the following tests establishes that a silicon NPN junction transistor is biased on?\r\nA. Measure base-to-emitter resistance with an ohmmeter; it should be approximately\r\n6 to 7 ohms\r\nB. Measure base-to-emitter resistance with an ohmmeter; it should be approximately 0.6 to 0.7 ohms\r\nC. Measure base-to-emitter voltage with a voltmeter; it should be approximately \r\n6 to 7 volts\r\nD. Measure base-to-emitter voltage with a voltmeter; it should be approximately\r\n0.6 to 0.7 volts\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4A11", "question": "Which of these instruments could be used for detailed analysis of digital signals?\r\nA. Dip meter\r\nB. Oscilloscope\r\nC. Ohmmeter\r\nD. Q meter\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4A12", "question": "Which of the following procedures is an important precaution to follow when connecting a spectrum analyzer to a transmitter output?\r\nA. Use high quality double shielded coaxial cables to reduce signal losses\r\nB. Attenuate the transmitter output going to the spectrum analyzer\r\nC. Match the antenna to the load\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4B01", "question": "Which of the following factors most affects the accuracy of a frequency counter?\r\nA. Input attenuator accuracy\r\nB. Time base accuracy\r\nC. Decade divider accuracy\r\nD. Temperature coefficient of the logic\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4B02", "question": "What is an advantage of using a bridge circuit to measure impedance?\r\nA. It provides an excellent match under all conditions\r\nB. It is relatively immune to drift in the signal generator source\r\nC. The measurement is based on obtaining a signal null, which can be done very precisely\r\nD. It can display results directly in Smith chart format\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4B03", "question": "If a frequency counter with a specified accuracy of +/- 1.0 ppm reads 146,520,000 Hz, what is the most the actual frequency being measured could differ from the reading?\r\nA. 165.2 Hz\r\nB. 14.652 kHz\r\nC. 146.52 Hz\r\nD. 1.4652 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4B04", "question": "If a frequency counter with a specified accuracy of +/- 0.1 ppm reads 146,520,000 Hz, what is the most the actual frequency being measured could differ from the reading?\r\nA. 14.652 Hz\r\nB. 0.1 MHz\r\nC. 1.4652 Hz\r\nD. 1.4652 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4B05", "question": "If a frequency counter with a specified accuracy of +/- 10 ppm reads 146,520,000 Hz, what is the most the actual frequency being measured could differ from the reading?\r\nA. 146.52 Hz\r\nB. 10 Hz\r\nC. 146.52 kHz\r\nD. 1465.20 Hz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4B06", "question": "How much power is being absorbed by the load when a directional power meter connected between a transmitter and a terminating load reads 100 watts forward power and 25 watts reflected power?\r\nA. 100 watts\r\nB. 125 watts\r\nC. 25 watts\r\nD. 75 watts\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4B07", "question": "Which of the following is good practice when using an oscilloscope probe?\r\nA. Keep the signal ground connection of the probe as short as possible\r\nB. Never use a high impedance probe to measure a low impedance circuit\r\nC. Never use a DC-coupled probe to measure an AC circuit\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4B08", "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a good DC voltmeter?\r\nA. High reluctance input\r\nB. Low reluctance input\r\nC. High impedance input\r\nD. Low impedance input\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4B09", "question": "What is indicated if the current reading on an RF ammeter placed in series with the antenna feed line of a transmitter increases as the transmitter is tuned to resonance?\r\nA. There is possibly a short to ground in the feed line\r\nB. The transmitter is not properly neutralized\r\nC. There is an impedance mismatch between the antenna and feed line\r\nD. There is more power going into the antenna\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4B10", "question": "Which of the following describes a method to measure intermodulation distortion in an SSB transmitter?\r\nA. Modulate the transmitter with two non-harmonically related radio frequencies and observe the RF output with a spectrum analyzer\r\nB. Modulate the transmitter with two non-harmonically related audio frequencies and observe the RF output with a spectrum analyzer\r\nC. Modulate the transmitter with two harmonically related audio frequencies and observe the RF output with a peak reading wattmeter\r\nD. Modulate the transmitter with two harmonically related audio frequencies and observe the RF output with a logic analyzer\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4B11", "question": "How should a portable antenna analyzer be connected when measuring antenna resonance and feed point impedance?\r\nA. Loosely couple the analyzer near the antenna base\r\nB. Connect the analyzer via a high-impedance transformer to the antenna\r\nC. Connect the antenna and a dummy load to the analyzer\r\nD. Connect the antenna feed line directly to the analyzer's connector\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4B12", "question": "What is the significance of voltmeter sensitivity expressed in ohms per volt?\r\nA. The full scale reading of the voltmeter multiplied by its ohms per volt rating will provide the input impedance of the voltmeter\r\nB. When used as a galvanometer, the reading in volts multiplied by the ohms/volt will determine the power drawn by the device under test\r\nC. When used as an ohmmeter, the reading in ohms divided by the ohms/volt will determine the voltage applied to the circuit\r\nD. When used as an ammeter, the full scale reading in amps divided by ohms/volt will determine the size of shunt needed\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4B13", "question": "How is the compensation of an oscilloscope probe typically adjusted?\r\nA. A square wave is displayed and the probe is adjusted until the horizontal portions of the displayed wave are as nearly flat as possible\r\nB. A high frequency sine wave is displayed and the probe is adjusted for maximum amplitude\r\nC. A frequency standard is displayed and the probe is adjusted until the deflection time is accurate\r\nD. A DC voltage standard is displayed and the probe is adjusted until the displayed voltage is accurate\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4B14", "question": "What happens if a dip meter is too tightly coupled to a tuned circuit being checked?\r\nA. Harmonics are generated\r\nB. A less accurate reading results\r\nC. Cross modulation occurs\r\nD. Intermodulation distortion occurs\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4B15", "question": "Which of the following can be used as a relative measurement of the Q for a series-tuned circuit?\r\nA. The inductance to capacitance ratio\r\nB. The frequency shift\r\nC. The bandwidth of the circuit's frequency response\r\nD. The resonant frequency of the circuit\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C01", "question": "What is an effect of excessive phase noise in the local oscillator section of a receiver?\r\nA. It limits the receiver's ability to receive strong signals\r\nB. It reduces receiver sensitivity\r\nC. It decreases receiver third-order intermodulation distortion dynamic range\r\nD. It can cause strong signals on nearby frequencies to interfere with reception of weak signals\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E4C02", "question": "Which of the following portions of a receiver can be effective in eliminating image signal interference?\r\nA. A front-end filter or pre-selector\r\nB. A narrow IF filter\r\nC. A notch filter\r\nD. A properly adjusted product detector\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4C03", "question": "What is the term for the blocking of one FM phone signal by another, stronger FM phone signal?\r\nA. Desensitization\r\nB. Cross-modulation interference\r\nC. Capture effect\r\nD. Frequency discrimination\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C04", "question": "What is the definition of the noise figure of a receiver?\r\nA. The ratio of atmospheric noise to phase noise\r\nB. The noise bandwidth in Hertz compared to the theoretical bandwidth of a resistive network\r\nC. The ratio of thermal noise to atmospheric noise\r\nD. The ratio in dB of the noise generated by the receiver compared to the theoretical minimum noise\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4C05", "question": "What does a value of -174 dBm/Hz represent with regard to the noise floor of a receiver?\r\nA. The minimum detectable signal as a function of receive frequency\r\nB. The theoretical noise at the input of a perfect receiver at room temperature\r\nC. The noise figure of a 1 Hz bandwidth receiver\r\nD. The galactic noise contribution to minimum detectable signal\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C06", "question": "A CW receiver with the AGC off has an equivalent input noise power density of -174 dBm/Hz.  What would be the level of an unmodulated carrier input to this receiver that would yield an audio output SNR of 0 dB in a 400 Hz noise bandwidth? \r\nA. 174 dBm\r\nB. -164 dBm\r\nC. -155 dBm\r\nD. -148 dBm\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4C07", "question": "What does the MDS of a receiver represent?\r\nA. The meter display sensitivity \r\nB. The minimum discernible signal\r\nC. The multiplex distortion stability\r\nD. The maximum detectable spectrum\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4C08", "question": "How might lowering the noise figure affect receiver performance? \r\nA. It would reduce the signal to noise ratio \r\nB. It would improve weak signal sensitivity\r\nC. It would reduce bandwidth\r\nD. It would increase bandwidth\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4C09", "question": "Which of the following choices is a good reason for selecting a high frequency for the design of the IF in a conventional HF or VHF communications receiver?\r\nA. Fewer components in the receiver\r\nB. Reduced drift\r\nC. Easier for front-end circuitry to eliminate image responses\r\nD. Improved receiver noise figure\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4C10", "question": "Which of the following is a desirable amount of selectivity for an amateur RTTY HF receiver?\r\nA. 100 Hz\r\nB. 300 Hz\r\nC. 6000 Hz\r\nD. 2400 Hz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E4C11", "question": "Which of the following is a desirable amount of selectivity for an amateur SSB phone receiver?\r\nA. 1 kHz\r\nB. 2.4 kHz\r\nC. 4.2 kHz\r\nD. 4.8 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C12", "question": "What is an undesirable effect of using too wide a filter bandwidth in the IF section of a receiver?\r\nA. Output-offset overshoot\r\nB. Filter ringing\r\nC. Thermal-noise distortion\r\nD. Undesired signals may be heard\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E4C13", "question": "How does a narrow-band roofing filter affect receiver performance?\r\nA. It improves sensitivity by reducing front end noise\r\nB. It improves intelligibility by using low Q circuitry to reduce ringing\r\nC. It improves dynamic range by attenuating strong signals near the receive frequency\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C14", "question": "On which of the following frequencies might a signal be transmitting which is generating a spurious image signal in a receiver tuned to 14.300 MHz and which uses a 455 kHz IF frequency?\r\nA. 13.845 MHz\r\nB. 14.755 MHz\r\nC. 14.445 MHz\r\nD. 15.210 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E4C15", "question": "What is the primary source of noise that can be heard from an HF receiver with an antenna connected?\r\nA. Detector noise\r\nB. Induction motor noise\r\nC. Receiver front-end noise\r\nD. Atmospheric noise\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5A01", "question": "What can cause the voltage across reactances in series to be larger than the voltage applied to them?\r\nA. Resonance\r\nB. Capacitance\r\nC. Conductance\r\nD. Resistance\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A02", "question": "What is resonance in an electrical circuit?\r\nA. The highest frequency that will pass current\r\nB. The lowest frequency that will pass current\r\nC. The frequency at which the capacitive reactance equals the inductive reactance\r\nD. The frequency at which the reactive impedance equals the resistive impedance\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5A03", "question": "What is the magnitude of the impedance of a series RLC circuit at resonance?\r\nA. High, as compared to the circuit resistance\r\nB. Approximately equal to capacitive reactance\r\nC. Approximately equal to inductive reactance\r\nD. Approximately equal to circuit resistance\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5A04", "question": "What is the magnitude of the impedance of a circuit with a resistor, an inductor and a capacitor all in parallel, at resonance?\r\nA. Approximately equal to circuit resistance\r\nB. Approximately equal to inductive reactance\r\nC. Low, as compared to the circuit resistance\r\nD. Approximately equal to capacitive reactance\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5A05", "question": "What is the magnitude of the current at the input of a series RLC circuit as the frequency goes through resonance?\r\nA. Minimum\r\nB. Maximum\r\nC. R/L\r\nD. L/R\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5A06", "question": "What is the magnitude of the circulating current within the components of a parallel LC circuit at resonance?\r\nA. It is at a minimum\r\nB. It is at a maximum\r\nC. It equals 1 divided by the quantity 2 times Pi, multiplied by the square root of inductance L multiplied by capacitance C\r\nD. It equals 2 multiplied by Pi, multiplied by frequency \"F\", multiplied by inductance \"L\"\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5A07", "question": "What is the magnitude of the current at the input of a parallel RLC circuit at resonance?\r\nA. Minimum\r\nB. Maximum\r\nC. R/L\r\nD. L/R\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A08", "question": "What is the phase relationship between the current through and the voltage across a series resonant circuit at resonance?\r\nA. The voltage leads the current by 90 degrees\r\nB. The current leads the voltage by 90 degrees\r\nC. The voltage and current are in phase\r\nD. The voltage and current are 180 degrees out of phase\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A09", "question": "What is the phase relationship between the current through and the voltage across a parallel resonant circuit at resonance?\r\nA. The voltage leads the current by 90 degrees\r\nB. The current leads the voltage by 90 degrees\r\nC. The voltage and current are in phase\r\nD. The voltage and current are 180 degrees out of phase\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5A10", "question": "What is the half-power bandwidth of a parallel resonant circuit that has a resonant frequency of 1.8 MHz and a Q of 95?\r\nA. 18.9 kHz\r\nB. 1.89 kHz\r\nC. 94.5 kHz\r\nD. 9.45 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A11", "question": "What is the half-power bandwidth of a parallel resonant circuit that has a resonant frequency of 7.1 MHz and a Q of 150?\r\nA. 157.8 Hz\r\nB. 315.6 Hz\r\nC. 47.3 kHz\r\nD. 23.67 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A12", "question": "What is the half-power bandwidth of a parallel resonant circuit that has a resonant frequency of 3.7 MHz and a Q of 118?\r\nA. 436.6 kHz\r\nB. 218.3 kHz\r\nC. 31.4 kHz\r\nD. 15.7 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5A13", "question": "What is the half-power bandwidth of a parallel resonant circuit that has a resonant frequency of 14.25 MHz and a Q of 187?\r\nA. 38.1 kHz\r\nB. 76.2 kHz\r\nC. 1.332 kHz\r\nD. 2.665 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5A14", "question": "What is the resonant frequency of a series RLC circuit if R is 22 ohms, L is 50 microhenrys and C is 40 picofarads?\r\nA. 44.72 MHz\r\nB. 22.36 MHz\r\nC. 3.56 MHz\r\nD. 1.78 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5A15", "question": "What is the resonant frequency of a series RLC circuit if R is 56 ohms, L is 40 microhenrys and C is 200 picofarads?\r\nA. 3.76 MHz\r\nB. 1.78 MHz\r\nC. 11.18 MHz\r\nD. 22.36 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5A16", "question": "What is the resonant frequency of a parallel RLC circuit if R is 33 ohms, L is 50 microhenrys and C is 10 picofarads?\r\nA. 23.5 MHz\r\nB. 23.5 kHz\r\nC. 7.12 kHz\r\nD. 7.12 MHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5A17", "question": "What is the resonant frequency of a parallel RLC circuit if R is 47 ohms, L is 25 microhenrys and C is 10 picofarads?\r\nA. 10.1 MHz\r\nB. 63.2 MHz\r\nC. 10.1 kHz\r\nD. 63.2 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5B01", "question": "What is the term for the time required for the capacitor in an RC circuit to be charged to 63.2% of the applied voltage?\r\nA. An exponential rate of one\r\nB. One time constant\r\nC. One exponential period\r\nD. A time factor of one\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5B02", "question": "What is the term for the time it takes for a charged capacitor in an RC circuit to discharge to 36.8% of its initial voltage?\r\nA. One discharge period\r\nB. An exponential discharge rate of one\r\nC. A discharge factor of one\r\nD. One time constant\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5B03", "question": "The capacitor in an RC circuit is discharged to what percentage of the starting voltage after two time constants?\r\nA. 86.5%\r\nB. 63.2%\r\nC. 36.8%\r\nD. 13.5%\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5B04", "question": "What is the time constant of a circuit having two 220-microfarad capacitors and two 1-megohm resistors, all in parallel?\r\nA. 55 seconds\r\nB. 110 seconds\r\nC. 440 seconds\r\nD. 220 seconds\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5B05", "question": "How long does it take for an initial charge of 20 V DC to decrease to 7.36 V DC in a 0.01-microfarad capacitor when a 2-megohm resistor is connected across it?\r\nA. 0.02 seconds\r\nB. 0.04 seconds\r\nC. 20 seconds\r\nD. 40 seconds\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5B06", "question": "How long does it take for an initial charge of 800 V DC to decrease to 294 V DC in a 450-microfarad capacitor when a 1-megohm resistor is connected across it?\r\nA. 4.50 seconds\r\nB. 9 seconds\r\nC. 450 seconds\r\nD. 900 seconds\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5B07", "question": "What is the phase angle between the voltage across and the current through a series RLC circuit if XC is 500 ohms, R is 1 kilohm, and XL is 250 ohms?\r\nA. 68.2 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nB. 14.0 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nC. 14.0 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nD. 68.2 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5B08", "question": "What is the phase angle between the voltage across and the current through a series RLC circuit if XC is 100 ohms, R is 100 ohms, and XL is 75 ohms?\r\nA. 14 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nB. 14 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nC. 76 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nD. 76 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5B09", "question": "What is the relationship between the current through a capacitor and the voltage across a capacitor?\r\nA. Voltage and current are in phase\r\nB. Voltage and current are 180 degrees out of phase\r\nC. Voltage leads current by 90 degrees\r\nD. Current leads voltage by 90 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5B10", "question": "What is the relationship between the current through an inductor and the voltage across an inductor?\r\nA. Voltage leads current by 90 degrees\r\nB. Current leads voltage by 90 degrees\r\nC. Voltage and current are 180 degrees out of phase\r\nD. Voltage and current are in phase\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5B11", "question": "What is the phase angle between the voltage across and the current through a series RLC circuit if XC is 25 ohms, R is 100 ohms, and XL is 50 ohms?\r\nA. 14 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nB. 14 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nC. 76 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nD. 76 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5B12", "question": "What is the phase angle between the voltage across and the current through a series RLC circuit if XC is 75 ohms, R is 100 ohms, and XL is 50 ohms?\r\nA. 76 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nB. 14 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nC. 14 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nD. 76 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5B13", "question": "What is the phase angle between the voltage across and the current through a series RLC circuit if XC is 250 ohms, R is 1 kilohm, and XL is 500 ohms?\r\nA. 81.47 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nB. 81.47 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\nC. 14.04 degrees with the voltage lagging the current\r\nD. 14.04 degrees with the voltage leading the current\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C01", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 100-ohm-reactance inductor in series with a 100-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 121 ohms at an angle of 35 degrees\r\nB. 141 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\nC. 161 ohms at an angle of 55 degrees\r\nD. 181 ohms at an angle of 65 degrees \r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C02", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 100-ohm-reactance inductor, a 100-ohm-reactance capacitor, and a 100-ohm resistor, all connected in series?\r\nA. 100 ohms at an angle of 90 degrees\r\nB. 10 ohms at an angle of 0 degrees\r\nC. 10 ohms at an angle of 90 degrees\r\nD. 100 ohms at an angle of 0 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C03", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 300-ohm-reactance capacitor, a 600-ohm-reactance inductor, and a 400-ohm resistor, all connected in series?\r\nA. 500 ohms at an angle of 37 degrees\r\nB. 900 ohms at an angle of 53 degrees\r\nC. 400 ohms at an angle of 0 degrees\r\nD. 1300 ohms at an angle of 180 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C04", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 400-ohm-reactance capacitor in series with a 300-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 240 ohms at an angle of 36.9 degrees\r\nB. 240 ohms at an angle of -36.9 degrees\r\nC. 500 ohms at an angle of 53.1 degrees\r\nD. 500 ohms at an angle of -53.1 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C05", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 400-ohm-reactance inductor in parallel with a 300-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 240 ohms at an angle of 36.9 degrees\r\nB. 240 ohms at an angle of -36.9 degrees\r\nC. 500 ohms at an angle of 53.1 degrees\r\nD. 500 ohms at an angle of -53.1 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C06", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 100-ohm-reactance capacitor in series with a 100-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 121 ohms at an angle of -25 degrees\r\nB. 191 ohms at an angle of -85 degrees\r\nC. 161 ohms at an angle of -65 degrees\r\nD. 141 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5C07", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network comprised of a 100-ohm-reactance capacitor in parallel with a 100-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 31 ohms at an angle of -15 degrees\r\nB. 51 ohms at an angle of -25 degrees\r\nC. 71 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\nD. 91 ohms at an angle of -65 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C08", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a network comprised of a 300-ohm-reactance inductor in series with a 400-ohm resistor?\r\nA. 400 ohms at an angle of 27 degrees\r\nB. 500 ohms at an angle of 37 degrees\r\nC. 500 ohms at an angle of 47 degrees\r\nD. 700 ohms at an angle of 57 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C09", "question": "When using rectangular coordinates to graph the impedance of a circuit, what does the horizontal axis represent?\r\nA. Resistive component\r\nB. Reactive component\r\nC. The sum of the reactive and resistive components\r\nD. The difference between the resistive and reactive components\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C10", "question": "When using rectangular coordinates to graph the impedance of a circuit, what does the vertical axis represent?\r\nA. Resistive component\r\nB. Reactive component\r\nC. The sum of the reactive and resistive components\r\nD. The difference between the resistive and reactive components\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5C11", "question": "What do the two numbers represent that are used to define a point on a graph using rectangular coordinates?\r\nA. The magnitude and phase of the point\r\nB. The sine and cosine values\r\nC. The coordinate values along the horizontal and vertical axes\r\nD. The tangent and cotangent values\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C12", "question": "If you plot the impedance of a circuit using the rectangular coordinate system and find the impedance point falls on the right side of the graph on the horizontal axis, what do you know about the circuit?\r\nA. It has to be a direct current circuit\r\nB. It contains resistance and capacitive reactance\r\nC. It contains resistance and inductive reactance\r\nD. It is equivalent to a pure resistance\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C13", "question": "What coordinate system is often used to display the resistive, inductive, and/or capacitive reactance components of an impedance?\r\nA. Maidenhead grid\r\nB. Faraday grid\r\nC. Elliptical coordinates \r\nD. Rectangular coordinates\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C14", "question": "What coordinate system is often used to display the phase angle of a circuit containing resistance, inductive and/or capacitive reactance?\r\nA. Maidenhead grid\r\nB. Faraday grid\r\nC. Elliptical coordinates\r\nD. Polar coordinates\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C15", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a circuit of 100 -j100 ohms impedance?\r\nA. 141 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\nB. 100 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\nC. 100 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\nD. 141 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C16", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a circuit that has an admittance of 7.09 millisiemens at 45 degrees?\r\nA. 5.03 E-06 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\nB. 141 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\nC. 19,900 ohms at an angle of -45 degrees\r\nD. 141 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E5C17", "question": "In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a circuit that has an admittance of 5 millisiemens at -30 degrees?\r\nA. 173 - j100 ohms\r\nB. 200 + j100 ohms\r\nC. 173 + j100 ohms\r\nD. 200 - j100 ohms\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C18", "question": "In polar coordinates, what is the impedance of a series circuit consisting of a resistance of 4 ohms, an inductive reactance of 4 ohms, and a capacitive reactance of 1 ohm?\r\nA. 6.4 ohms at an angle of 53 degrees\r\nB. 5 ohms at an angle of 37 degrees\r\nC. 5 ohms at an angle of 45 degrees\r\nD. 10 ohms at an angle of -51 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C19", "question": "Which point on Figure E5-2 best represents that impedance of a series circuit consisting of a 400 ohm resistor and a 38 picofarad capacitor at 14 MHz?\r\nA. Point 2\r\nB. Point 4\r\nC. Point 5\r\nD. Point 6\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E5C20", "question": "Which point in Figure E5-2 best represents the impedance of a series circuit consisting of a 300 ohm resistor and an 18 microhenry inductor at 3.505 MHz?\r\nA. Point 1\r\nB. Point 3\r\nC. Point 7\r\nD. Point 8\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C21", "question": "Which point on Figure E5-2 best represents the impedance of a series circuit consisting of a 300 ohm resistor and a 19 picofarad capacitor at 21.200 MHz?\r\nA. Point 1\r\nB. Point 3\r\nC. Point 7\r\nD. Point 8\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E5C22", "question": "In rectangular coordinates, what is the impedance of a network consisting of a 10-microhenry inductor in series with a 40-ohm resistor at 500 MHz?\r\nA. 40 + j31,400\r\nB. 40 - j31,400\r\nC. 31,400 + j40\r\nD. 31,400 - j40\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E5C23", "question": "Which point on Figure E5-2 best represents the impedance of a series circuit consisting of a 300-ohm resistor, a 0.64-microhenry inductor and an 85-picofarad capacitor at 24.900 MHz?\r\nA. Point 1\r\nB. Point 3\r\nC. Point 5\r\nD. Point 8\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A01", "question": "In what application is gallium arsenide used as a semiconductor material in preference to germanium or silicon?\r\nA. In high-current rectifier circuits\r\nB. In high-power audio circuits\r\nC. At microwave frequencies\r\nD. At very low frequency RF circuits\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6A02", "question": "Which of the following semiconductor materials contains excess free electrons?\r\nA. N-type\r\nB. P-type\r\nC. Bipolar\r\nD. Insulated gate\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A03", "question": "What are the majority charge carriers in P-type semiconductor material?\r\nA. Free neutrons\r\nB. Free protons\r\nC. Holes\r\nD. Free electrons\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A04", "question": "What is the name given to an impurity atom that adds holes to a semiconductor crystal structure?\r\nA. Insulator impurity\r\nB. N-type impurity\r\nC. Acceptor impurity\r\nD. Donor impurity\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A05", "question": "What is the alpha of a bipolar junction transistor?\r\nA. The change of collector current with respect to base current\r\nB. The change of base current with respect to collector current\r\nC. The change of collector current with respect to emitter current\r\nD. The change of collector current with respect to gate current\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6A06", "question": "What is the beta of a bipolar junction transistor?\r\nA. The frequency at which the current gain is reduced to 1\r\nB. The change in collector current with respect to base current\r\nC. The breakdown voltage of the base to collector junction\r\nD. The switching speed of the transistor\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6A07", "question": "In Figure E6-1, what is the schematic symbol for a PNP transistor?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 4\r\nD. 5\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6A08", "question": "What term indicates the frequency at which the grounded-base current gain of a transistor has decreased to 0.7 of the gain obtainable at 1 kHz?\r\nA. Corner frequency\r\nB. Alpha rejection frequency\r\nC. Beta cutoff frequency\r\nD. Alpha cutoff frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6A09", "question": "What is a depletion-mode FET?\r\nA. An FET that exhibits a current flow between source and drain when no gate voltage is applied\r\nB. An FET that has no current flow between source and drain when no gate voltage is applied\r\nC. Any FET without a channel\r\nD. Any FET for which holes are the majority carriers\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6A10", "question": "In Figure E6-2, what is the schematic symbol for an N-channel dual-gate MOSFET?\r\nA. 2\r\nB. 4\r\nC. 5\r\nD. 6\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6A11", "question": "In Figure E6-2, what is the schematic symbol for a P-channel junction FET?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 3\r\nD. 6\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6A12", "question": "Why do many MOSFET devices have internally connected Zener diodes on the gates?\r\nA. To provide a voltage reference for the correct amount of reverse-bias gate voltage\r\nB. To protect the substrate from excessive voltages\r\nC. To keep the gate voltage within specifications and prevent the device from overheating\r\nD. To reduce the chance of the gate insulation being punctured by static discharges or excessive voltages\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A13", "question": "What do the initials CMOS stand for?\r\nA. Common Mode Oscillating System\r\nB. Complementary Mica-Oxide Silicon\r\nC. Complementary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor\r\nD. Common Mode Organic Silicon\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6A14", "question": "How does DC input impedance at the gate of a field-effect transistor compare with the DC input impedance of a bipolar transistor?\r\nA. They are both low impedance\r\nB. An FET has low input impedance; a bipolar transistor has high input impedance\r\nC. An FET has high input impedance; a bipolar transistor has low input impedance\r\nD. They are both high impedance\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6A15", "question": "Which of the following semiconductor materials contains an excess of holes in the outer shell of electrons?\r\nA. N-type\r\nB. P-type\r\nC. Superconductor-type\r\nD. Bipolar-type\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6A16", "question": "What are the majority charge carriers in N-type semiconductor material?\r\nA. Holes\r\nB. Free electrons\r\nC. Free protons\r\nD. Free neutrons\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6A17", "question": "What are the names of the three terminals of a field-effect transistor?\r\nA. Gate 1, gate 2, drain\r\nB. Emitter, base, collector\r\nC. Emitter, base 1, base 2\r\nD. Gate, drain, source\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6B01", "question": "What is the most useful characteristic of a Zener diode?\r\nA. A constant current drop under conditions of varying voltage\r\nB. A constant voltage drop under conditions of varying current\r\nC. A negative resistance region\r\nD. An internal capacitance that varies with the applied voltage\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6B02", "question": "What is an important characteristic of a Schottky diode as compared to an ordinary silicon diode when used as a power supply rectifier?\r\nA. Much higher reverse voltage breakdown\r\nB. Controlled reverse avalanche voltage\r\nC. Enhanced carrier retention time\r\nD. Less forward voltage drop\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6B03", "question": "What special type of diode is capable of both amplification and oscillation?\r\nA. Point contact\r\nB. Zener\r\nC. Tunnel\r\nD. Junction\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6B04", "question": "What type of semiconductor device is designed for use as a voltage-controlled capacitor?\r\nA. Varactor diode\r\nB. Tunnel diode\r\nC. Silicon-controlled rectifier\r\nD. Zener diode\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6B05", "question": "What characteristic of a PIN diode makes it useful as an RF switch or attenuator?\r\nA. Extremely high reverse breakdown voltage\r\nB. Ability to dissipate large amounts of power\r\nC. Reverse bias controls its forward voltage drop\r\nD. A large region of intrinsic material\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6B06", "question": "Which of the following is a common use of a hot-carrier diode?\r\nA. As balanced mixers in FM generation\r\nB. As a variable capacitance in an automatic frequency control circuit\r\nC. As a constant voltage reference in a power supply\r\nD. As a VHF / UHF mixer or detector\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6B07", "question": "What is the failure mechanism when a junction diode fails due to excessive current? \r\nA. Excessive inverse voltage\r\nB. Excessive junction temperature\r\nC. Insufficient forward voltage\r\nD. Charge carrier depletion\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6B08", "question": "Which of the following describes a type of semiconductor diode?\r\nA. Metal-semiconductor junction\r\nB. Electrolytic rectifier\r\nC. CMOS-field effect\r\nD. Thermionic emission diode \r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6B09", "question": "What is a common use for point contact diodes?\r\nA. As a constant current source\r\nB. As a constant voltage source\r\nC. As an RF detector\r\nD. As a high voltage rectifier\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6B10", "question": "In Figure E6-3, what is the schematic symbol for a light-emitting diode?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 5\r\nC. 6\r\nD. 7\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6B11", "question": "What is used to control the attenuation of RF signals by a PIN diode?\r\nA. Forward DC bias current\r\nB. A sub-harmonic pump signal\r\nC. Reverse voltage larger than the RF signal\r\nD. Capacitance of an RF coupling capacitor\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6B12", "question": "What is one common use for PIN diodes?\r\nA. As a constant current source\r\nB. As a constant voltage source\r\nC. As an RF switch\r\nD. As a high voltage rectifier\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6B13", "question": "What type of bias is required for an LED to emit light?\r\nA. Reverse bias\r\nB. Forward bias\r\nC. Zero bias\r\nD. Inductive bias\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6C01", "question": "What is the recommended power supply voltage for TTL series integrated circuits?\r\nA. 12 volts\r\nB. 1.5 volts\r\nC. 5 volts\r\nD. 13.6 volts\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6C02", "question": "What logic state do the inputs of a TTL device assume if they are left open?\r\nA. A logic-high state\r\nB. A logic-low state\r\nC. The device becomes randomized and will not provide consistent high or low-logic states\r\nD. Open inputs on a TTL device are ignored\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6C03", "question": "Which of the following describes tri-state logic?\r\nA. Logic devices with 0, 1, and high impedance output states\r\nB. Logic devices that utilize ternary math\r\nC. Low power logic devices designed to operate at 3 volts\r\nD. Proprietary logic devices manufactured by Tri-State Devices\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6C04", "question": "Which of the following is the primary advantage of tri-state logic?\r\nA. Low power consumption\r\nB. Ability to connect many device outputs to a common bus \r\nC. High speed operation\r\nD. More efficient arithmetic operations\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6C05", "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of CMOS logic devices over TTL devices?\r\nA. Differential output capability\r\nB. Lower distortion\r\nC. Immune to damage from static discharge\r\nD. Lower power consumption\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6C06", "question": "Why do CMOS digital integrated circuits have high immunity to noise on the input signal or power supply?\r\nA. Larger bypass capacitors are used in CMOS circuit design\r\nB. The input switching threshold is about two times the power supply voltage\r\nC. The input switching threshold is about one-half the power supply voltage\r\nD. Input signals are stronger\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E6C07", "question": "In Figure E6-5, what is the schematic symbol for an AND gate?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 3\r\nD. 4\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6C08", "question": "In Figure E6-5, what is the schematic symbol for a NAND gate?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 3\r\nD. 4\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E6C09", "question": "In Figure E6-5, what is the schematic symbol for an OR gate?\r\nA. 2\r\nB. 3\r\nC. 4\r\nD. 6\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6C10", "question": "In Figure E6-5, what is the schematic symbol for a NOR gate?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 3\r\nD. 4\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6C11", "question": "In Figure E6-5, what is the schematic symbol for the NOT operation (inverter)?\r\nA. 2\r\nB. 4\r\nC. 5\r\nD. 6\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E6C12", "question": "What is BiCMOS logic?\r\nA. A logic device with two CMOS circuits per package\r\nB. An FET logic family based on bimetallic semiconductors\r\nC. A logic family based on bismuth CMOS devices\r\nD. An integrated circuit logic family using both bipolar and CMOS transistors\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E6C13", "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of BiCMOS logic?\r\nA. Its simplicity results in much less expensive devices than standard CMOS\r\nB. It is totally immune to electrostatic damage\r\nC. It has the high input impedance of CMOS and the low output impedance of bipolar transistors\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7A01", "question": "Which of the following is a bistable circuit?\r\nA. An \"AND\" gate\r\nB. An \"OR\" gate\r\nC. A flip-flop\r\nD. A clock\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7A02", "question": "How many output level changes are obtained for every two trigger pulses applied to the input of a T flip-flop circuit?\r\nA. None\r\nB. One\r\nC. Two\r\nD. Four\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7A03", "question": "Which of the following can divide the frequency of a pulse train by 2?\r\nA. An XOR gate\r\nB. A flip-flop\r\nC. An OR gate\r\nD. A multiplexer\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7A04", "question": "How many flip-flops are required to divide a signal frequency by 4?\r\nA. 1\r\nB. 2\r\nC. 4\r\nD. 8\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7A05", "question": "Which of the following is a circuit that continuously alternates between two states without an external clock?\r\nA. Monostable multivibrator\r\nB. J-K flip-flop\r\nC. T flip-flop\r\nD. Astable multivibrator\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7A06", "question": "What is a characteristic of a monostable multivibrator?\r\nA. It switches momentarily to the opposite binary state and then returns, after a set time, to its original state\r\nB. It is a clock that produces a continuous square wave oscillating between 1 and 0\r\nC. It stores one bit of data in either a 0 or 1 state\r\nD. It maintains a constant output voltage, regardless of variations in the input voltage\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7A07", "question": "What logical operation does a NAND gate perform?\r\nA. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output only when all inputs are logic \"0\"\r\nB. It produces a logic \"1\" at its output only when all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nC. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output if some but not all of its inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nD. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output only when all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7A08", "question": "What logical operation does an OR gate perform?\r\nA. It produces a logic \"1\" at its output if any or all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nB. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output if all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nC. It only produces a logic \"0\" at its output when all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nD. It produces a logic \"1\" at its output if all inputs are logic \"0\"\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7A09", "question": "What logical operation is performed by a two-input exclusive NOR gate?\r\nA. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output only if all inputs are logic \"0\"\r\nB. It produces a logic \"1\" at its output only if all inputs are logic \"1\"\r\nC. It produces a logic \"0\" at its output if any single input is a logic \"1\"?\r\nD. It produces a logic \"1\" at its output if any single input is a logic \"1\"?\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7A10", "question": "What is a truth table? \r\nA. A table of logic symbols that indicate the high logic states of an op-amp\r\nB. A diagram showing logic states when the digital device's output is true\r\nC. A list of inputs and corresponding outputs for a digital device\r\nD. A table of logic symbols that indicates the low logic states of an op-amp\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7A11", "question": "What is the name for logic which represents a logic \"1\" as a high voltage?\r\nA. Reverse Logic\r\nB. Assertive Logic\r\nC. Negative logic\r\nD. Positive Logic\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7A12", "question": "What is the name for logic which represents a logic \"0\" as a high voltage?\r\nA. Reverse Logic\r\nB. Assertive Logic\r\nC. Negative logic\r\nD. Positive Logic\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7A13", "question": "What is an SR or RS flip-flop? \r\nA. A speed-reduced logic device with high power capability\r\nB. A set/reset flip-flop whose output is low when R is high and S is low, high when S is high and R is low, and unchanged when both inputs are low\r\nC. A speed-reduced logic device with very low voltage operation capability\r\nD. A set/reset flip-flop that toggles whenever the T input is pulsed, unless both inputs are high\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7A14", "question": "What is a JK flip-flop?\r\nA. A flip-flop similar to an RS except that it toggles when both J and K are high\r\nB. A flip-flop utilizing low power, low temperature Joule-Kelvin devices\r\nC. A flip-flop similar to a D flip-flop except that it triggers on the negative clock edge\r\nD. A flip-flop originally developed in Japan and Korea which has very low power consumption\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7A15", "question": "What is a D flip-flop?\r\nA. A flip-flop whose output takes on the state of the D input when the clock signal transitions from low to high\r\nB. A differential class D amplifier used as a flip-flop circuit\r\nC. A dynamic memory storage element\r\nD. A flip-flop whose output is capable of both positive and negative voltage excursions\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B01", "question": "For what portion of a signal cycle does a Class AB amplifier operate?\r\nA. More than 180 degrees but less than 360 degrees\r\nB. Exactly 180 degrees\r\nC. The entire cycle\r\nD. Less than 180 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B02", "question": "What is a Class D amplifier?\r\nA. A type of amplifier that uses switching technology to achieve high efficiency\r\nB. A low power amplifier using a differential amplifier for improved linearity\r\nC. An amplifier using drift-mode FETs for high efficiency\r\nD. A frequency doubling amplifier\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B03", "question": "Which of the following forms the output of a class D amplifier circuit?\r\nA. A low-pass filter to remove switching signal components\r\nB. A high-pass filter to compensate for low gain at low frequencies\r\nC. A matched load resistor to prevent damage by switching transients\r\nD. A temperature-compensated load resistor to improve linearity \r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B04", "question": "Where on the load line of a Class A common emitter amplifier would bias normally be set?\r\nA. Approximately half-way between saturation and cutoff\r\nB. Where the load line intersects the voltage axis\r\nC. At a point where the bias resistor equals the load resistor\r\nD. At a point where the load line intersects the zero bias current curve\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7B05", "question": "What can be done to prevent unwanted oscillations in an RF power amplifier?\r\nA. Tune the stage for maximum SWR\r\nB. Tune both the input and output for maximum power\r\nC. Install parasitic suppressors and/or neutralize the stage \r\nD. Use a phase inverter in the output filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7B06", "question": "Which of the following amplifier types reduces or eliminates even-order harmonics?\r\nA. Push-push\r\nB. Push-pull\r\nC. Class C\r\nD. Class AB\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7B07", "question": "Which of the following is a likely result when a Class C amplifier is used to amplify a single-sideband phone signal?\r\nA. Reduced intermodulation products\r\nB. Increased overall intelligibility\r\nC. Signal inversion\r\nD. Signal distortion and excessive bandwidth\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7B08", "question": "How can an RF power amplifier be neutralized?\r\nA. By increasing the driving power\r\nB. By reducing the driving power\r\nC. By feeding a 180-degree out-of-phase portion of the output back to the input\r\nD. By feeding an in-phase component of the output back to the input\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7B09", "question": "Which of the following describes how the loading and tuning capacitors are to be adjusted when tuning a vacuum tube RF power amplifier that employs a pi-network output circuit? \r\nA. The loading capacitor is set to maximum capacitance and the tuning capacitor is adjusted for minimum allowable plate current\r\nB. The tuning capacitor is set to maximum capacitance and the loading capacitor is adjusted for minimum plate permissible current\r\nC. The loading capacitor is adjusted to minimum plate current while alternately adjusting the tuning capacitor for maximum allowable plate current\r\nD. The tuning capacitor is adjusted for minimum plate current, while the loading capacitor is adjusted for maximum permissible plate current\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7B10", "question": "In Figure E7-1, what is the purpose of R1 and R2?\r\nA. Load resistors\r\nB. Fixed bias\r\nC. Self bias\r\nD. Feedback\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7B11", "question": "In Figure E7-1, what is the purpose of R3?\r\nA. Fixed bias\r\nB. Emitter bypass\r\nC. Output load resistor\r\nD. Self bias\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7B12", "question": "What type of circuit is shown in Figure E7-1?\r\nA. Switching voltage regulator\r\nB. Linear voltage regulator\r\nC. Common emitter amplifier\r\nD. Emitter follower amplifier\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B13", "question": "In Figure E7-2, what is the purpose of R?\r\nA. Emitter load\r\nB. Fixed bias\r\nC. Collector load\r\nD. Voltage regulation\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B14", "question": "In Figure E7-2, what is the purpose of C2?\r\nA. Output coupling\r\nB. Emitter bypass\r\nC. Input coupling\r\nD. Hum filtering\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7B15", "question": "What is one way to prevent thermal runaway in a bipolar transistor amplifier?\r\nA. Neutralization\r\nB. Select transistors with high beta\r\nC. Use a resistor in series with the emitter\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B16", "question": "What is the effect of intermodulation products in a linear power amplifier?\r\nA. Transmission of spurious signals \r\nB. Creation of parasitic oscillations\r\nC. Low efficiency\r\nD. All of these choices are correct \r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B17", "question": "Why are third-order intermodulation distortion products of particular concern in linear power amplifiers?\r\nA. Because they are relatively close in frequency to the desired signal\r\nB. Because they are relatively far in frequency from the desired signal\r\nC. Because they invert the sidebands causing distortion\r\nD. Because they maintain the sidebands, thus causing multiple duplicate signals \r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7B18", "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic of a grounded-grid amplifier?\r\nA. High power gain\r\nB. High filament voltage\r\nC. Low input impedance\r\nD. Low bandwidth\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7B19", "question": "What is a klystron?\r\nA. A high speed multivibrator\r\nB. An electron-coupled oscillator utilizing a pentode vacuum tube\r\nC. An oscillator utilizing ceramic elements to achieve stability\r\nD. A VHF, UHF, or microwave vacuum tube that uses velocity modulation\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7B20", "question": "What is a parametric amplifier?\r\nA. A type of bipolar operational amplifier with excellent linearity derived from use of very high voltage on the collector\r\nB. A low-noise VHF or UHF amplifier relying on varying reactance for amplification\r\nC. A high power amplifier for HF application utilizing the Miller effect to increase gain\r\nD. An audio push-pull amplifier using silicon carbide transistors for extremely low noise\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7B21", "question": "Which of the following devices is generally best suited for UHF or microwave power amplifier applications?\r\nA. Field effect transistor\r\nB. Nuvistor\r\nC. Silicon controlled rectifier\r\nD. Triac\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7C01", "question": "How are the capacitors and inductors of a low-pass filter Pi-network arranged between the network's input and output? \r\nA. Two inductors are in series between the input and output, and a capacitor is connected between the two inductors and ground\r\nB. Two capacitors are in series between the input and output and an inductor is connected between the two capacitors and ground\r\nC. An inductor is connected between the input and ground, another inductor is connected between the output and ground, and a capacitor is connected between the input and output \r\nD. A capacitor is connected between the input and ground, another capacitor is connected between the output and ground, and an inductor is connected between input and output\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7C02", "question": "A T-network with series capacitors and a parallel shunt inductor has which of the following properties?\r\nA. It is a low-pass filter\r\nB. It is a band-pass filter\r\nC. It is a high-pass filter\r\nD. It is a notch filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7C03", "question": "What advantage does a Pi-L-network have over a Pi-network for impedance matching between the final amplifier of a vacuum-tube transmitter and an antenna?\r\nA. Greater harmonic suppression\r\nB. Higher efficiency\r\nC. Lower losses\r\nD. Greater transformation range\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7C04", "question": "How does an impedance-matching circuit transform a complex impedance to a resistive impedance?\r\nA. It introduces negative resistance to cancel the resistive part of impedance\r\nB. It introduces transconductance to cancel the reactive part of impedance\r\nC. It cancels the reactive part of the impedance and changes the resistive part to a desired value\r\nD. Network resistances are substituted for load resistances and reactances are matched to the resistances\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7C05", "question": "Which filter type is described as having ripple in the passband and a sharp cutoff?\r\nA. A Butterworth filter\r\nB. An active LC filter\r\nC. A passive op-amp filter\r\nD. A Chebyshev filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7C06", "question": "What are the distinguishing features of an elliptical filter?\r\nA. Gradual passband rolloff with minimal stop band ripple\r\nB. Extremely flat response over its pass band with gradually rounded stop band corners\r\nC. Extremely sharp cutoff with one or more notches in the stop band\r\nD. Gradual passband rolloff with extreme stop band ripple\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7C07", "question": "What kind of filter would you use to attenuate an interfering carrier signal while receiving an SSB transmission?\r\nA. A band-pass filter\r\nB. A notch filter\r\nC. A Pi-network filter\r\nD. An all-pass filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7C08", "question": "What kind of digital signal processing audio filter might be used to remove unwanted noise from a received SSB signal?\r\nA. An adaptive filter\r\nB. A crystal-lattice filter\r\nC. A Hilbert-transform filter\r\nD. A phase-inverting filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7C09", "question": "What type of digital signal processing filter might be used to generate an SSB signal?\r\nA. An adaptive filter\r\nB. A notch filter\r\nC. A Hilbert-transform filter\r\nD. An elliptical filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7C10", "question": "Which of the following filters would be the best choice for use in a 2 meter repeater duplexer?\r\nA. A crystal filter\r\nB. A cavity filter\r\nC. A DSP filter\r\nD. An L-C filter\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E7C11", "question": "Which of the following is the common name for a filter network which is equivalent to two L networks connected back-to-back with the inductors in series and the capacitors in shunt at the input and output?\r\nA. Pi-L\r\nB. Cascode\r\nC. Omega\r\nD. Pi \r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E7C12", "question": "Which of the following describes a Pi-L network used for matching a vacuum-tube final amplifier to a 50-ohm unbalanced output?\r\nA. A Phase Inverter Load network\r\nB. A Pi network with an additional series inductor on the output\r\nC. A network with only three discrete parts\r\nD. A matching network in which all components are isolated from ground\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E7C13", "question": "What is one advantage of a Pi matching network over an L matching network consisting of a single inductor and a single capacitor?\r\nA. The Q of Pi networks can be varied depending on the component values chosen\r\nB. L networks cannot perform impedance transformation\r\nC. Pi networks have fewer components \r\nD. Pi networks are designed for balanced input and output\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E7C14", "question": "Which of these modes is most affected by non-linear phase response in a receiver IF filter?\r\nA. Meteor Scatter\r\nB. Single-Sideband voice\r\nC. Digital\r\nD. Video\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8A01", "question": "What type of wave is made up of a sine wave plus all of its odd harmonics?\r\nA. A square wave\r\nB. A sine wave\r\nC. A cosine wave\r\nD. A tangent wave\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8A02", "question": "What type of wave has a rise time significantly faster than its fall time (or vice versa)?\r\nA. A cosine wave\r\nB. A square wave\r\nC. A sawtooth wave\r\nD. A sine wave\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8A03", "question": "What type of wave is made up of sine waves of a given fundamental frequency plus all its harmonics?\r\nA. A sawtooth wave\r\nB. A square wave\r\nC. A sine wave\r\nD. A cosine wave\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8A04", "question": "What is equivalent to the root-mean-square value of an AC voltage?\r\nA. The AC voltage found by taking the square of the average value of the peak AC voltage\r\nB. The DC voltage causing the same amount of heating in a given resistor as the corresponding peak AC voltage\r\nC. The DC voltage causing the same amount of heating in a resistor as the corresponding RMS AC voltage\r\nD. The AC voltage found by taking the square root of the average AC value\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8A05", "question": "What would be the most accurate way of measuring the RMS voltage of a complex waveform?\r\nA. By using a grid dip meter\r\nB. By measuring the voltage with a D'Arsonval meter\r\nC. By using an absorption wavemeter\r\nD. By measuring the heating effect in a known resistor\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8A06", "question": "What is the approximate ratio of PEP-to-average power in a typical single-sideband phone signal?\r\nA. 2.5 to 1\r\nB. 25 to 1\r\nC. 1 to 1\r\nD. 100 to 1\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8A07", "question": "What determines the PEP-to-average power ratio of a single-sideband phone signal?\r\nA. The frequency of the modulating signal\r\nB. The characteristics of the modulating signal\r\nC. The degree of carrier suppression\r\nD. The amplifier gain\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8A08", "question": "What is the period of a wave?\r\nA. The time required to complete one cycle\r\nB. The number of degrees in one cycle\r\nC. The number of zero crossings in one cycle\r\nD. The amplitude of the wave\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8A09", "question": "What type of waveform is produced by human speech?\r\nA. Sinusoidal\r\nB. Logarithmic\r\nC. Irregular\r\nD. Trapezoidal\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8A10", "question": "Which of the following is a distinguishing characteristic of a pulse waveform?\r\nA. Regular sinusoidal oscillations\r\nB. Narrow bursts of energy separated by periods of no signal\r\nC. A series of tones that vary between two frequencies\r\nD. A signal that contains three or more discrete tones\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8A11", "question": "What is one use for a pulse modulated signal?\r\nA. Linear amplification\r\nB. PSK31 data transmission\r\nC. Multiphase power transmission\r\nD. Digital data transmission\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8A12", "question": "What type of information can be conveyed using digital waveforms?\r\nA. Human speech\r\nB. Video signals\r\nC. Data\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8A13", "question": "What is an advantage of using digital signals instead of analog signals to convey the same information?\r\nA. Less complex circuitry is required for digital signal generation and detection\r\nB. Digital signals always occupy a narrower bandwidth\r\nC. Digital signals can be regenerated multiple times without error\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8A14", "question": "Which of these methods is commonly used to convert analog signals to digital signals?\r\nA. Sequential sampling\r\nB. Harmonic regeneration\r\nC. Level shifting\r\nD. Phase reversal\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8A15", "question": "What would the waveform of a stream of digital data bits look like on a conventional oscilloscope?\r\nA. A series of sine waves with evenly spaced gaps\r\nB. A series of pulses with varying patterns\r\nC. A running display of alpha-numeric characters\r\nD. None of the above; this type of signal cannot be seen on a conventional oscilloscope\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8B01", "question": "What is the term for the ratio between the frequency deviation of an RF carrier wave, and the modulating frequency of its corresponding FM-phone signal?\r\nA. FM compressibility\r\nB. Quieting index\r\nC. Percentage of modulation\r\nD. Modulation index\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8B02", "question": "How does the modulation index of a phase-modulated emission vary with RF carrier frequency (the modulated frequency)?\r\nA. It increases as the RF carrier frequency increases\r\nB. It decreases as the RF carrier frequency increases\r\nC. It varies with the square root of the RF carrier frequency\r\nD. It does not depend on the RF carrier frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8B03", "question": "What is the modulation index of an FM-phone signal having a maximum frequency deviation of 3000 Hz either side of the carrier frequency, when the modulating frequency is 1000 Hz?\r\nA. 3\r\nB. 0.3\r\nC. 3000\r\nD. 1000\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8B04", "question": "What is the modulation index of an FM-phone signal having a maximum carrier deviation of plus or minus 6 kHz when modulated with a 2-kHz modulating frequency?\r\nA. 6000\r\nB. 3\r\nC. 2000\r\nD. 1/3\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8B05", "question": "What is the deviation ratio of an FM-phone signal having a maximum frequency swing of plus-or-minus 5 kHz when the maximum modulation frequency is 3 kHz?\r\nA. 60\r\nB. 0.167\r\nC. 0.6\r\nD. 1.67\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8B06", "question": "What is the deviation ratio of an FM-phone signal having a maximum frequency swing of plus or minus 7.5 kHz when the maximum modulation frequency is 3.5 kHz?\r\nA. 2.14\r\nB. 0.214\r\nC. 0.47\r\nD. 47\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8B07", "question": "When using a pulse-width modulation system, why is the transmitter's peak power greater than its average power?\r\nA. The signal duty cycle is less than 100%\r\nB. The signal reaches peak amplitude only when voice modulated\r\nC. The signal reaches peak amplitude only when voltage spikes are generated within the modulator\r\nD. The signal reaches peak amplitude only when the pulses are also amplitude modulated\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8B08", "question": "What parameter does the modulating signal vary in a pulse-position modulation system?\r\nA. The number of pulses per second\r\nB. The amplitude of the pulses\r\nC. The duration of the pulses\r\nD. The time at which each pulse occurs\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8B09", "question": "What is meant by deviation ratio?\r\nA. The ratio of the audio modulating frequency to the center carrier frequency\r\nB. The ratio of the maximum carrier frequency deviation to the highest audio modulating frequency\r\nC. The ratio of the carrier center frequency to the audio modulating frequency\r\nD. The ratio of the highest audio modulating frequency to the average audio modulating frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8B10", "question": "Which of these methods can be used to combine several separate analog information streams into a single analog radio frequency signal?\r\nA. Frequency shift keying\r\nB. A diversity combiner\r\nC. Frequency division multiplexing\r\nD. Pulse compression\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8B11", "question": "Which of the following describes frequency division multiplexing?\r\nA. The transmitted signal jumps from band to band at a predetermined rate\r\nB. Two or more information streams are merged into a \"baseband\", which then modulates the transmitter\r\nC. The transmitted signal is divided into packets of information\r\nD. Two or more information streams are merged into a digital combiner, which then pulse position modulates the transmitter\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8B12", "question": "What is digital time division multiplexing?\r\nA. Two or more data streams are assigned to discrete sub-carriers on an FM transmitter\r\nB. Two or more signals are arranged to share discrete time slots of a data transmission\r\nC. Two or more data streams share the same channel by transmitting time of transmission as the sub-carrier \r\nD. Two or more signals are quadrature modulated to increase bandwidth efficiency\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8C01", "question": "Which one of the following digital codes consists of elements having unequal length?\r\nA. ASCII\r\nB. AX.25\r\nC. Baudot\r\nD. Morse code\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8C02", "question": "What are some of the differences between the Baudot digital code and ASCII?\r\nA. Baudot uses four data bits per character, ASCII uses seven or eight; Baudot uses one character as a shift code, ASCII has no shift code\r\nB. Baudot uses five data bits per character, ASCII uses seven or eight; Baudot uses two characters as shift codes, ASCII has no shift code\r\nC. Baudot uses six data bits per character, ASCII uses seven or eight; Baudot has no shift code, ASCII uses two characters as shift codes\r\nD. Baudot uses seven data bits per character, ASCII uses eight; Baudot has no shift code, ASCII uses two characters as shift codes\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8C03", "question": "What is one advantage of using the ASCII code for data communications?\r\nA. It includes built-in error-correction features\r\nB. It contains fewer information bits per character than any other code\r\nC. It is possible to transmit both upper and lower case text\r\nD. It uses one character as a shift code to send numeric and special characters\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8C04", "question": "What technique is used to minimize the bandwidth requirements of a PSK31 signal?\r\nA. Zero-sum character encoding\r\nB. Reed-Solomon character encoding\r\nC. Use of sinusoidal data pulses\r\nD. Use of trapezoidal data pulses\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8C05", "question": "What is the necessary bandwidth of a 13-WPM international Morse code transmission?\r\nA. Approximately 13 Hz\r\nB. Approximately 26 Hz\r\nC. Approximately 52 Hz\r\nD. Approximately 104 Hz\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E8C06", "question": "What is the necessary bandwidth of a 170-hertz shift, 300-baud ASCII transmission?\r\nA. 0.1 Hz\r\nB. 0.3 kHz\r\nC. 0.5 kHz\r\nD. 1.0 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8C07", "question": "What is the necessary bandwidth of a 4800-Hz frequency shift, 9600-baud ASCII FM transmission?\r\nA. 15.36 kHz\r\nB. 9.6 kHz\r\nC. 4.8 kHz\r\nD. 5.76 kHz\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8C08", "question": "What term describes a wide-bandwidth communications system in which the transmitted carrier frequency varies according to some predetermined sequence?\r\nA. Amplitude compandored single sideband\r\nB. AMTOR\r\nC. Time-domain frequency modulation\r\nD. Spread-spectrum communication\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8C09", "question": "Which of these techniques causes a digital signal to appear as wide-band noise to a conventional receiver?\r\nA. Spread-spectrum\r\nB. Independent sideband\r\nC. Regenerative detection\r\nD. Exponential addition\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E8C10", "question": "What spread-spectrum communications technique alters the center frequency of a conventional carrier many times per second in accordance with a pseudo-random list of channels?\r\nA. Frequency hopping\r\nB. Direct sequence\r\nC. Time-domain frequency modulation\r\nD. Frequency compandored spread-spectrum\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8C11", "question": "What spread-spectrum communications technique uses a high speed binary bit stream to shift the phase of an RF carrier?\r\nA. Frequency hopping\r\nB. Direct sequence\r\nC. Binary phase-shift keying\r\nD. Phase compandored spread-spectrum\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E8C12", "question": "What is the advantage of including a parity bit with an ASCII character stream?\r\nA. Faster transmission rate\r\nB. The signal can overpower interfering signals\r\nC. Foreign language characters can be sent\r\nD. Some types of errors can be detected\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E8C13", "question": "What is one advantage of using JT-65 coding?\r\nA. Uses only a 65 Hz bandwidth\r\nB. The ability to decode signals which have a very low signal to noise ratio\r\nC. Easily copied by ear if necessary\r\nD. Permits fast-scan TV transmissions over narrow bandwidth\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9A01", "question": "Which of the following describes an isotropic antenna?\r\nA. A grounded antenna used to measure earth conductivity\r\nB. A horizontally polarized antenna used to compare Yagi antennas\r\nC. A theoretical antenna used as a reference for antenna gain\r\nD. A spacecraft antenna used to direct signals toward the earth\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9A02", "question": "How much gain does a 1/2-wavelength dipole in free space have compared to an isotropic antenna?\r\nA. 1.55 dB\r\nB. 2.15 dB\r\nC. 3.05 dB\r\nD. 4.30 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9A03", "question": "Which of the following antennas has no gain in any direction?\r\nA. Quarter-wave vertical\r\nB. Yagi\r\nC. Half-wave dipole\r\nD. Isotropic antenna\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9A04", "question": "Why would one need to know the feed point impedance of an antenna?\r\nA. To match impedances in order to minimize standing wave ratio on the transmission line\r\nB. To measure the near-field radiation density from a transmitting antenna\r\nC. To calculate the front-to-side ratio of the antenna\r\nD. To calculate the front-to-back ratio of the antenna\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9A05", "question": "Which of the following factors may affect the feed point impedance of an antenna?\r\nA. Transmission-line length \r\nB. Antenna height, conductor length/diameter ratio and location of nearby conductive objects\r\nC. Constant feed point impedance\r\nD. Sunspot activity and time of day\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9A06", "question": "What is included in the total resistance of an antenna system?\r\nA. Radiation resistance plus space impedance\r\nB. Radiation resistance plus transmission resistance\r\nC. Transmission-line resistance plus radiation resistance\r\nD. Radiation resistance plus ohmic resistance\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9A07", "question": "What is a folded dipole antenna?\r\nA. A dipole one-quarter wavelength long\r\nB. A type of ground-plane antenna\r\nC. A dipole constructed from one wavelength of wire forming a very thin loop\r\nD. A dipole configured to provide forward gain \r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9A08", "question": "What is meant by antenna gain?\r\nA. The ratio relating the radiated signal strength of an antenna in the direction of maximum radiation to that of a reference antenna\r\nB. The ratio of the signal in the forward direction to that in the opposite direction\r\nC. The ratio of the amount of power radiated by an antenna compared to the transmitter output power\r\nD. The final amplifier gain minus the transmission-line losses, including any phasing lines present\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9A09", "question": "What is meant by antenna bandwidth?\r\nA. Antenna length divided by the number of elements\r\nB. The frequency range over which an antenna satisfies a performance requirement\r\nC. The angle between the half-power radiation points\r\nD. The angle formed between two imaginary lines drawn through the element ends\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9A10", "question": "How is antenna efficiency calculated?\r\nA. (radiation resistance / transmission resistance) x 100%\r\nB. (radiation resistance / total resistance) x 100%\r\nC. (total resistance / radiation resistance) x 100%\r\nD. (effective radiated power / transmitter output) x 100%\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9A11", "question": "Which of the following choices is a way to improve the efficiency of a ground-mounted quarter-wave vertical antenna?\r\nA. Install a good radial system\r\nB. Isolate the coax shield from ground\r\nC. Shorten the radiating element\r\nD. Reduce the diameter of the radiating element\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9A12", "question": "Which of the following factors determines ground losses for a ground-mounted vertical antenna operating in the 3-30 MHz range?\r\nA. The standing-wave ratio\r\nB. Distance from the transmitter\r\nC. Soil conductivity\r\nD. Take-off angle\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9A13", "question": "How much gain does an antenna have compared to a 1/2-wavelength dipole when it has 6 dB gain over an isotropic antenna?\r\nA. 3.85 dB\r\nB. 6.0 dB\r\nC. 8.15 dB\r\nD. 2.79 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9A14", "question": "How much gain does an antenna have compared to a 1/2-wavelength dipole when it has 12 dB gain over an isotropic antenna?\r\nA. 6.17 dB\r\nB. 9.85 dB\r\nC. 12.5 dB\r\nD. 14.15 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9A15", "question": "What is meant by the radiation resistance of an antenna?\r\nA. The combined losses of the antenna elements and feed line\r\nB. The specific impedance of the antenna\r\nC. The value of a resistance that would dissipate the same amount of power as that radiated from an antenna\r\nD. The resistance in the atmosphere that an antenna must overcome to be able to radiate a signal\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9B01", "question": "In the antenna radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-1, what is the 3-dB beamwidth?\r\nA. 75 degrees\r\nB. 50 degrees\r\nC. 25 degrees\r\nD. 30 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9B02", "question": "In the antenna radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-1, what is the front-to-back ratio?\r\nA. 36 dB\r\nB. 18 dB\r\nC. 24 dB\r\nD. 14 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9B03", "question": "In the antenna radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-1, what is the front-to-side ratio?\r\nA. 12 dB\r\nB. 14 dB\r\nC. 18 dB\r\nD. 24 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9B04", "question": "What may occur when a directional antenna is operated at different frequencies within the band for which it was designed?\r\nA. Feed point impedance may become negative\r\nB. The E-field and H-field patterns may reverse\r\nC. Element spacing limits could be exceeded\r\nD. The gain may change depending on frequency\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9B05", "question": "What usually occurs if a Yagi antenna is designed solely for maximum forward gain?\r\nA. The front-to-back ratio increases\r\nB. The front-to-back ratio decreases\r\nC. The frequency response is widened over the whole frequency band\r\nD. The SWR is reduced\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9B06", "question": "If the boom of a Yagi antenna is lengthened and the elements are properly retuned, what usually occurs?\r\nA. The gain increases\r\nB. The SWR decreases\r\nC. The front-to-back ratio increases\r\nD. The gain bandwidth decreases rapidly\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9B07", "question": "How does the total amount of radiation emitted by a directional gain antenna compare with the total amount of radiation emitted from an isotropic antenna, assuming each is driven by the same amount of power?\r\nA. The total amount of radiation from the directional antenna is increased by the gain of the antenna\r\nB. The total amount of radiation from the directional antenna is stronger by its front to back ratio\r\nC. They are the same\r\nD. The radiation from the isotropic antenna is 2.15 dB stronger than that from the directional antenna \r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9B08", "question": "How can the approximate beamwidth in a given plane of a directional antenna be determined?\r\nA. Note the two points where the signal strength of the antenna is 3 dB less than maximum and compute the angular difference\r\nB. Measure the ratio of the signal strengths of the radiated power lobes from the front and rear of the antenna\r\nC. Draw two imaginary lines through the ends of the elements and measure the angle between the lines\r\nD. Measure the ratio of the signal strengths of the radiated power lobes from the front and side of the antenna\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9B09", "question": "What type of computer program technique is commonly used for modeling antennas?\r\nA. Graphical analysis\r\nB. Method of Moments\r\nC. Mutual impedance analysis\r\nD. Calculus differentiation with respect to physical properties\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9B10", "question": "What is the principle of a Method of Moments analysis?\r\nA. A wire is modeled as a series of segments, each having a uniform value of current\r\nB. A wire is modeled as a single sine-wave current generator\r\nC. A wire is modeled as a series of points, each having a distinct location in space\r\nD. A wire is modeled as a series of segments, each having a distinct value of voltage across it\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9B11", "question": "What is a disadvantage of decreasing the number of wire segments in an antenna model below the guideline of 10 segments per half-wavelength?\r\nA. Ground conductivity will not be accurately modeled\r\nB. The resulting design will favor radiation of harmonic energy\r\nC. The computed feed point impedance may be incorrect\r\nD. The antenna will become mechanically unstable\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9B12", "question": "What is the far-field of an antenna?\r\nA. The region of the ionosphere where radiated power is not refracted\r\nB. The region where radiated power dissipates over a specified time period\r\nC. The region where radiated field strengths are obstructed by objects of reflection\r\nD. The region where the shape of the antenna pattern is independent of distance\r\n\r\n\r\nE9B13 (B)\r\nWhat does the abbreviation NEC stand for when applied to antenna modeling programs?\r\nA. Next Element Comparison\r\nB. Numerical Electromagnetics Code\r\nC. National Electrical Code\r\nD. Numeric Electrical Computation\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9B14", "question": "What type of information can be obtained by submitting the details of a proposed new antenna to a modeling program?\r\nA. SWR vs. frequency charts\r\nB. Polar plots of the far-field elevation and azimuth patterns\r\nC. Antenna gain \r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9C01", "question": "What is the radiation pattern of two 1/4-wavelength vertical antennas spaced 1/2-wavelength apart and fed 180 degrees out of phase?\r\nA. A cardioid\r\nB. Omnidirectional\r\nC. A figure-8 broadside to the axis of the array\r\nD. A figure-8 oriented along the axis of the array\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9C02", "question": "What is the radiation pattern of two 1/4-wavelength vertical antennas spaced 1/4-wavelength apart and fed 90 degrees out of phase?\r\nA. A cardioid\r\nB. A figure-8 end-fire along the axis of the array\r\nC. A figure-8 broadside to the axis of the array\r\nD. Omnidirectional\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9C03", "question": "What is the radiation pattern of two 1/4-wavelength vertical antennas spaced 1/2-wavelength apart and fed in phase?\r\nA. Omnidirectional\r\nB. A cardioid\r\nC. A Figure-8 broadside to the axis of the array\r\nD. A Figure-8 end-fire along the axis of the array\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9C04", "question": "Which of the following describes a basic unterminated rhombic antenna?\r\nA. Unidirectional; four-sides, each side one quarter-wavelength long; terminated in a resistance equal to its characteristic impedance\r\nB. Bidirectional; four-sides, each side one or more wavelengths long; open at the end opposite the transmission line connection\r\nC. Four-sides; an LC network at each corner except for the transmission connection;\r\nD. Four-sides, each of a different physical length\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9C05", "question": "What are the disadvantages of a terminated rhombic antenna for the HF bands?\r\nA. The antenna has a very narrow operating bandwidth\r\nB. The antenna produces a circularly polarized signal\r\nC. The antenna requires a large physical area and 4 separate supports\r\nD. The antenna is more sensitive to man-made static than any other type\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9C06", "question": "What is the effect of a terminating resistor on a rhombic antenna?\r\nA. It reflects the standing waves on the antenna elements back to the transmitter\r\nB. It changes the radiation pattern from bidirectional to unidirectional\r\nC. It changes the radiation pattern from horizontal to vertical polarization\r\nD. It decreases the ground loss\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9C07", "question": "What type of antenna pattern over real ground is shown in Figure E9-2?\r\nA. Elevation\r\nB. Azimuth\r\nC. Radiation resistance\r\nD. Polarization\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9C08", "question": "What is the elevation angle of peak response in the antenna radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-2?\r\nA. 45 degrees\r\nB. 75 degrees\r\nC. 7.5 degrees\r\nD. 25 degrees\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E9C09", "question": "What is the front-to-back ratio of the radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-2?\r\nA. 15 dB\r\nB. 28 dB\r\nC. 3 dB\r\nD. 24 dB\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E9C10", "question": "How many elevation lobes appear in the forward direction of the antenna radiation pattern shown in Figure E9-2?\r\nA. 4\r\nB. 3\r\nC. 1\r\nD. 7\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9C11", "question": "How is the far-field elevation pattern of a vertically polarized antenna affected by being mounted over seawater versus rocky ground?\r\nA. The low-angle radiation decreases\r\nB. The high-angle radiation increases\r\nC. Both the high- and low-angle radiation decrease\r\nD. The low-angle radiation increases\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E9C12", "question": "When constructing a Beverage antenna, which of the following factors should be included in the design to achieve good performance at the desired frequency?\r\nA. Its overall length must not exceed 1/4 wavelength \r\nB. It must be mounted more than 1 wavelength above ground\r\nC. It should be configured as a four-sided loop\r\nD. It should be one or more wavelengths long \r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E9C13", "question": "What is the main effect of placing a vertical antenna over an imperfect ground? \r\nA. It causes increased SWR\r\nB. It changes the impedance angle of the matching network\r\nC. It reduces low-angle radiation\r\nD. It reduces losses in the radiating portion of the antenna\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A01", "question": "What, if any, are the differences between the radiation produced by radioactive materials and the electromagnetic energy radiated by an antenna?\r\nA. There is no significant difference between the two types of radiation\r\nB. Only radiation produced by radioactivity can injure human beings\r\nC. Radioactive materials emit ionizing radiation, while RF signals have less energy and can only cause heating\r\nD. Radiation from an antenna will damage unexposed photographic film but ordinary radioactive materials do not cause this problem\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E0A02", "question": "When evaluating RF exposure levels from your station at a neighbor's home, what must you do?\r\nA. Make sure signals from your station are less than the controlled MPE limits\r\nB. Make sure signals from your station are less than the uncontrolled MPE limits\r\nC. You need only evaluate exposure levels on your own property\r\nD. Advise your neighbors of the results of your tests\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A03", "question": "Which of the following would be a practical way to estimate whether the RF fields produced by an amateur radio station are within permissible MPE limits?\r\nA. Use a calibrated antenna analyzer\r\nB. Use a hand calculator plus Smith-chart equations to calculate the fields\r\nC. Use an antenna modeling program to calculate field strength at accessible locations\r\nD. All of the choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A04", "question": "When evaluating a site with multiple transmitters operating at the same time, the operators and licensees of which transmitters are responsible for mitigating over-exposure situations?\r\nA. Only the most powerful transmitter\r\nB. Only commercial transmitters\r\nC. Each transmitter that produces 5% or more of its MPE exposure limit at accessible locations\r\nD. Each transmitter operating with a duty-cycle greater than 50%\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E0A05", "question": "What is one of the potential hazards of using microwaves in the amateur radio bands?\r\nA. Microwaves are ionizing radiation\r\nB. The high gain antennas commonly used can result in high exposure levels\r\nC. Microwaves often travel long distances by ionospheric reflection\r\nD. The extremely high frequency energy can damage the joints of antenna structures\r\n"}, {"answer": "D", "id": "E0A06", "question": "Why are there separate electric (E) and magnetic (H) field MPE limits?\r\nA. The body reacts to electromagnetic radiation from both the E and H fields\r\nB. Ground reflections and scattering make the field impedance vary with location\r\nC. E field and H field radiation intensity peaks can occur at different locations\r\nD. All of these choices are correct\r\n"}, {"answer": "B", "id": "E0A07", "question": "How may dangerous levels of carbon monoxide from an emergency generator be detected?\r\nA. By the odor\r\nB. Only with a carbon monoxide detector\r\nC. Any ordinary smoke detector can be used\r\nD. By the yellowish appearance of the gas\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A08", "question": "What does SAR measure?\r\nA. Synthetic Aperture Ratio of the human body\r\nB. Signal Amplification Rating\r\nC. The rate at which RF energy is absorbed by the body\r\nD. The rate of RF energy reflected from stationary terrain\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A09", "question": "Which insulating material commonly used as a thermal conductor for some types of electronic devices is extremely toxic if broken or crushed and the particles are accidentally inhaled?\r\nA. Mica\r\nB. Zinc oxide\r\nC. Beryllium Oxide\r\nD. Uranium Hexaflouride\r\n"}, {"answer": "A", "id": "E0A10", "question": "What material found in some electronic components such as high-voltage capacitors and transformers is considered toxic?\r\nA. Polychlorinated biphenyls\r\nB. Polyethylene\r\nC. Polytetrafluroethylene\r\nD. Polymorphic silicon\r\n"}, {"answer": "C", "id": "E0A11", "question": "Which of the following injuries can result from using high-power UHF or microwave transmitters?\r\nA. Hearing loss caused by high voltage corona discharge\r\nB. Blood clotting from the intense magnetic field\r\nC. Localized heating of the body from RF exposure in excess of the MPE limits\r\nD. Ingestion of ozone gas from the cooling system\r\n"}]